<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Dax Murray</title>
  <subtitle>Books. Coding. Feminism. (Cats.)</subtitle>
  <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog</id>
  <link href="http://daxmurray.com/blog"/>
  <link href="http://daxmurray.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-02-19T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Dax Murray</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Falsehoods Programmers Believe About Email Addresses</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/Falsehoods-Programmers-Believe-About-Email/"/>
    <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog/Falsehoods-Programmers-Believe-About-Email/</id>
    <published>2017-02-19T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-20T18:16:17-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dax Murray</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This blog is frustratingly dedicated to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ClassPass"&gt;ClassPass&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mindbodyonline"&gt;MindBodyOnline&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BookOutletcom"&gt;BookOutlet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awhile back, I changed my name. I had been using an email that contained my old name, so it was time for a new email, too. I had just bought http://dax.codes, and so my new email is &lt;strong&gt;**&lt;/strong&gt;@dax.codes. I didn't think this would be an issue. But wow, it is an issue. Since changing over to using this email full time, I have found some pretty abysmal ways to validate an email on the front end, preventing me from signing up for services, making purchases, filling out forms, and much much more. This blog may even be dedicated to places where I pointed out the ways in which they were preventing me from giving them money, only to be told they didn't actually want  my money! I've been told more often then I want to just get a new email. I actually want to never be told to just get a new email, for the record.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asking your user to get a whole new email just so that they can give you money is a really awful user experience. Before this, I was not an email expert. But now I've formed some pretty good opinions on front end and back end validations for email addresses. Email has been around since the 1960's, and by the 1970's took on a form that is recognized as the ancestor to today's email protocols. Early emails were similar to very early AIM, where both users had to be online in order to send and recieve. Most email systems today use STMP, or Simple Mail Transfer Protocol. Users can then use IMAP or POP to retrieve their messages from the server where the message is stored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order for a user to get their messages, they need a unique email address to log into, whether they are doing that via a web-based client (gmail, yahoo, aol) or a application like Outlook. Because many people use email addresses from free, web-based services, like gmail, it's easy to forget that the format of username@hostname.com format is not the only format for an email address. This oversight leads to people relying on fallbacks like a regex validation that might look like: [^@]+@[^@]+.[a-zA-Z]{2,11}. This says any character, then an at sign, then any characters, then a period, then any letters(at least two, but no more than 11). This was, I am embarassed to admit, a regex I was using as a fallback for when HTML5 failed. Let's break it down a little bit, and why, at the time I thought it might work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, the part before the @ sign can literally have any character, even if gmail won't let you. The first part of the email address, where you might do first.lastnname, is called the local part, and according to &lt;a href="https://www.ietf.org/rfc/rfc5321.txt"&gt;2.3.10 of RFC 2821 on SMTP&lt;/a&gt;, the local part is only to be deciphered by the host: "the local-part MUST be interpreted and assigned semantics only by the host specified in the domain part of the address.". So gmail lets you use only a few characters, they are the host and they get to decide that. But if you set up your own email server? You could let yourself use !#$%^&amp;amp;*()_+=- and more to your hearts content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc3696#section-3"&gt;RFC 3696&lt;/a&gt; these are officially valid email addresses, please note the use of \ to escape spaces, additional @'s, the use of "", starting with $, and more in the local part of the email address:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Abc\@def@example.com
Fred\ Bloggs@example.com
"Abc@def"@example.com
"Fred Bloggs"@example.com
customer/department=shipping@example.com
$A12345@example.com
!def!xyz%abc@example.com
_somename@example.com
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second part of the email address is the domain name, this is usually gmail, yahoo, aol, or whatever you have! If you own a domain, you can set up an email server with it, or you can pay Google and they can manange it. So my domain is dax. In this case, email address standards don't apply, but domain standards do, which you can find in &lt;a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc1035"&gt;RFC 1035&lt;/a&gt;. So the regex I showed above has, again, any character. While there are standards that restrict this, if someone is doing their own hosting and not using a top level domain, they might ignore those standards. If your a software dev, you do a lot of your own hosting on localhost. While in dev mode, you could create an email at me@localhost and you should be able to fill out your form and get an email response. If you wanted me@localhost-b&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last part is the top-level domain, usually, if I am going to hit a snag, this is where it is. &lt;a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc3696"&gt;According to RCF-3696&lt;/a&gt;, email validitiy shouldn't be tested against a list of top level domains. While there were only a few in the 1990's, two letter country codes have been gradually added, and there is an ever increasing number of valid non-country domains&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of the first quarter of 2003, the list of valid, non-country,
   top-level domains was .AERO, .BIZ, .COM, .COOP, .EDU, .GOV, .INFO,
   .INT, .MIL, .MUSEUM, .NAME, .NET, .ORG, .PRO, and .ARPA.  ICANN is
   expected to expand that list at regular intervals, so the list that
   appears here should not be used in testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the example regex above, a top level domain is required, and as discussed above, you don't actually need a top level domain to have a valid email. Furthermore, the above example says a TLD is 2 to 11 letters. That was based on the fact that the &lt;em&gt;current&lt;/em&gt; longest top level domain is .technology, but as there are many new top level domains coming out each year, it is very possible that there are longer ones on the horizon. While that seems to be a bad idea from a user experience level (shorter URL's are better, after all), it might be a good idea for marketing. My current primary web presence is http://dax.codes. The TLD is 5 letters, and wisdom of less letters might have tempted me to make an offer on dax.com, I wanted something memorable, that conveyed what the site was about (it's about me doing code). So the regex example accounts for my email address, but it might not account for a hypothetical email from yoshi\ p@xiv.finalfantasyteam. (yes, you can have spaces in the local part of your email by using the backslash to escape.) Currently, finalfantasyteam isn't a TLD, but who even knows, it might be one day. In this future, I would now be grep-ing my entire repo directory on my laptop looking for where I had used this regex and replacing the 11 with 16. And any attempt to use @localhost emails for testing would be failed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the @ sign is not necessarily necessary, there are intranets used in government, and many other places, where there is an internal email system, which can send and recieve emails just using the local part. So if you are building an app as part of a contract that would run on this company or organizations intranet, and you want it to send emails to their intranet email, your regex would fail here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how do you make sure someone is using a valid email with your app? Rely on confirmation emails. After the user has given you the necessary information, send an email to them with a link they must click. Don't authenticate the user on your app until that link has been clicked. Some places will sign a person in and let them use the app, and have a yellow or red banner at the top saying that you haven't confirmed your email yet (twitter does this currently). But you can still use most of the functionality without that confirmation. In your users table, have confirmed_email: boolean, and have part of user authentication be that confirmed_email is true. You might be sending emails off into the void for a bit, but you will not be accidentally turning away users who are trying to give you money.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Snake Love</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/snake-love/"/>
    <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog/snake-love/</id>
    <published>2017-02-13T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-14T20:39:50-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dax Murray</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/me_an_melusina.jpg" alt="Me holding my snake in front of my face" style="max-width: 50%; float: right;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I adopted a snake recently! Her name is Melusina, she was hatched in July 2016 and she is a yellow belly ball python. "Yellow belly" is her "morph" - what snake breeders use to describe patterns / markings / genetics. There's a whole system of dominate / co-dominate / recessive traits breeding that goes on to make some really awesome looking snakes. "Ball python" is the type of snake she is. Ball pythons are medium sized snakes that are non-venomous. They are constrictors, which means they kill their prey by squeezing them. They are also sometimes called "royal pythons" because royalty in sub-Saharan nations would sometimes wear them as jewelry. The monikor "ball python" comes from the fact that balling up is their response to pretty much anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/melusina_flames.JPG" alt="a ball python's backside as wrapped around a human wrist" style="max-width: 50%; float: left;" /&gt;
Yellow bellies have "flames" coming up from their bellies. So the pattern would normally be solid black, but instead, inside of the black, there are some orange-ish flames. You can see my snakes "flames" pretty well in the light. Yellow bellies also have an orange smudgey triangle on their heads. It's a morph that was first "discovered" in 1999, and it's a dominante gene. If you breed two yellow bellies together, you will probably get a super yellow belly, or what is known sometimes as an ivory, which is a snake that is mostly all off- white with a very faint yellow pattern. Melusina's dad was an ivory ball python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/world_of_pets.jpg" alt="farm animals at a pet expo, including goats and miniature horse" style="max-width: 50%; float: right;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've wanted a pet snake for awhile now, and have had my heart set on ball pythons since college, when one of my sorority sisters had a snake she kept in her dorm room and sometimes brought out for various campus events. A few weeks ago I was at the Maryland World of Pets Expo with my friend &lt;a href="http://uncorkedunwrapped.com"&gt;Liz&lt;/a&gt; and we had a ton of fun meeting goats, alpacas, very large rabbits, very small horses, ducks, dogs who did tricks, cats who slept, and lots and lots of very good dogs that Brent would approve of. We eventually found our way to the reptile dealers, where some woman was very non-chalantly holding a scorpion. Down a little ways from her was a ton of snakes, and I asked if I could hold one. I ended up holding a banana ball python, and really wanted to take her home with me. The dealer said he could set up a kit for me and I could take the snake home with me today! However, the partner that I live with is kinda really scared of snakes. I texted anyways asking if it was ok, very jokingly. I didn't get a response until after we were pulling out of the expo and heading back home. But the response was "Sure."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I spent the next few days talking it over, doing some research, and triple checking that my partner was actually fine with me getting a python. I called up some Petco's and Petsmarts to ask if they carried ball pythons, not because I wanted to purchase one from a chain retailer, but because I wanted to know if they might have the correct supplies for me. I got on craigslist and tried to find some snakes for adoption on there, but wasn't really finding any ball pythons. I googled for reptile stores in DC, and found one in Baltimore. Finally I did the desperate thing and got on reddit, which is how I found &lt;a href="http://morphmarket.com"&gt;MorphMarket&lt;/a&gt;, which is a pretty new site, but it has inventory of hundreds of reptile breeders and reptile specialty stores, you can look by reptile type, and on the ball python end you could look on genetics, making it easy to find an Ivory (or "super yellow belly") or Banana or Albino or really any other fancy patterns. I used their map functionality to find a breeder (&lt;a href="https://www.osmunreptiles.com/"&gt;Osmun Reptiles&lt;/a&gt;) about twenty minutes from my place, and used MorphMarket to send an inquire about a hatchling he had. He responsed very promptly, and gave me a ton of good info about her. I let him know I was pretty local and while he could ship the snake, I wanted to pick her up in person and not risk it with it being winter. Breeders can often overnight live reptiles by putting heating packs in the box, but if there is a problem and it gets delayed, or it gets left on your porch and you don't get home for several hours, it can turn disasterous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With payment made and pick up arranged for the upcoming weekend, I started shopping for supplies for her. I waded through tons of care sheets from pet stores and pet supply manufacturers like Zoo Med and Zilla. I watched YouTube Videos from LLL Reptiles and other places like them on how to set up a snake habitate. They all had glass acquariums with screen tops, and said you needed a heating lamp and an under tank heater, like a heating pad. They said you could get a cheap substrate like aspen shavings, and that the heater went on one side (which would be your snakes "hot" side) and the other side should not have a heater (and be your snakes "cool" side). Most of them said you should have a "hide" on each side, or a small dark enclosure in which your snake could hide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went back to reddit, ready to ask questions that the videos did not answer. I went back /after/ I'd purchased a lot of stuff. I started reading, and reading, and reading, not quiet wanting to ever actually need to post on reddit, and therefore combing through the archives trying to find what I needed. The first thing I found was a rather tragic post of someone's snake removing the stick on thermometer in the tank and getting stuck to it. This did not end well for the snake, and I was really sad. I then checked the thermometer I'd purchased. Oops. Same one. I learned that if there is an adhesive surface in the tank, the snake will find a way to get to it, so don't stick anything to the tank walls with tape, sticky tack, command strips, etc. If you need to attach something to the tanks inner walls, use hot glue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next thing I learned is that tanks are actually pretty bad for snakes! They don't hold heat, and with the screen top, it makes keeping the necessary heat in a constant battle. With a screen top, humditiy also becomes difficult to maintain. A ball pythons cool side should always be above 75 F, and the warm side should not ever be above 95 F, preferrably no higher than 90 F. The humidity should always be above 50%, and during shed, it should be around 70%. I also had purchased aspen bedding, which sucks up a lot of moisture, and misting your tank to try to get the humidity up could easily cause a mold outbreak in the aspen substrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found links to places like &lt;a href="http://www.apcages.com/home/"&gt;Animal Plastics&lt;/a&gt;  and &lt;a href="http://pvccages.com/"&gt;PVC Cages&lt;/a&gt;. I know the webpages is incredibly sketchy looking, but multiple people on reddit vouched for it, and several of them I saw in multiple threads explaining how to treat snake emergencies, so I started to trust them even though they were often not the most pleasant people, since they obviously just wanted snakes to live a happy life. These enclsures were advocated as a pretty optimal place to keep a pet snake. You can buy the enclosure, the heating sources, and lighting sources all at once. They apparently last decades, and require very little by way of cleaning and upkeep. I'd already sunk a ton of money into my supplies, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already knew that baby ball pythons can get really scared of large spaces, so while mine is just a hatchling, she would need a smaller space. So I decided to try to make the best of what I had, and save up for a larger enclosure for her by way of either PVC Cages or Animal Plastics. First, I got two &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2kQT4XB"&gt;heating pads&lt;/a&gt;. These are adhesive, and meant to be stuck to the outside bottom of your tank, not the inside. The thing they don't tell you is that they can't really be bent, and bending them breaks them. So once it's on the tank, it's not coming off without breaking. However, as I learned on reddit, you can use the adhesive to stick it on tin foil, and then tape it onto the bottom outside of the tank with a heat resistant tape. I put one at each end of my tank, since it's glass and not great at heat. I then plugged them both into a &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2kHYwcU"&gt;thermostat&lt;/a&gt;. On the one side I set the temperature to 90F, and on the other, 78F. These aren't the most expensive thermostats, and there are some that are $600 USD and made specifically for reptile enclosures. This way the temperature in the enclsure would always be above 75F. The thermostates have probes to check the temperature, they come with suction cups. Don't be tempted to put the probes inside the enclosure. Instead put them in between the heating pad and the glass, the snake will find a way to move them, and if the snake sits on it in the enclsure, you might end up with a wrong temperature reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then got a foam poster board, and cut it up and taped it to the back and the sides of the glass tank. This achieves two things. First, it makes the snake feel more secure. Second, it acts as insulation for the glass, helping to keep the heat in. In addition, I got saran wrap and covered abut two-thirds of the screen top. I was now getting the right temperature readings, so I didn't need to rely on a heat lamp, and could use LED lights to illuminate the enclosure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ordered bricks of &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2leYqNx"&gt;coconut fiber&lt;/a&gt; substrate, which I then soaked in water and put in. I didn't soak it in too much water, just enough to get it to not be so compact. This helped keep the humidity up, and didn't have such a high risk of mold that the aspen bedding did. YOu don't need much substrate, you could actually get away with using papertowels as substrate if you wanted. I like the look of the coconut husks and it's helpful during shed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made the mistake of ordering too small a water bowel, none of the care sheets or videos from Big Brands explained that the snake should be able to fully fit into the water bowel in some manner. So I made sure to go to a pet store and find an appropriate sized one instead of relying on internet measurements to try to figure out if she could fit in it. Snakes will sometimes soak themselves in their water bowels to help with shedding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the probes used for the thermostates, I have two other &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2lf6HRy"&gt;thermometers and hygrometers&lt;/a&gt; in the enclosure. One at each end, so that I can always have a feel for what is going on. I plan on getting an infrared thermometer in the future, but right now these are working well and I am making sure that it stays above 50%. So far with the coconut husks and the fact that I myself prefer at least 50% humidity, this isn't a problem. Melusina's enclsure is in a room where I have a giant 3.5 gallon humdifier that I have set up for my own personal comfort, I understand not everyone does this though, so you might have to take other measure to keep your snake happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have two &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2kIadjK"&gt;hides&lt;/a&gt; for her, and she spends a lot of the day in them. The hides are identical. As I learned, hides should be the same size, and those hollowed out logs don't really give them security, even if one end is butted up against glass. So far Melusina really likes the ones I have for her. You can use pretty much anything for hides as long as they are the same size. The reason for this is that in the wild a snake could have its pick of hides, and so will look for one that meets its temperate and size needs for its own security. If one is too small or too big, it can go find another one. In captivity, a snake can't be Goldilocks. The snake can really only pick between the hides that we give. So if the snake feels safe in the warm hide, but needs to thermoregulate and be cooler, the snake might have to choose between feeling safe and thermoregulating. She has some fake plants, too. Most of which I bought in the fish section, because for some reason they were cheaper. She also has a fake log that stays in the middle of the tank that she will sometimes climb on at night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for food, I order her food online. Be warned, the shipping is a big pricy, and it will come packaged with dry ice. But the mice and rats themselves are pretty cheap. I bought her 50 frozen prey for $12, plus $50 shipping. The breeder suggested to me &lt;a href="http://www.perfectprey.com/"&gt;PerfectPrey&lt;/a&gt; but there are other places you can buy too. I can't so far find frozen prey local to me (which is weird, this is a major city…but I guess DC is a fairly conservative city as far as pets go?). I also picked up some tongs which I use to hold the prey when I attempt to feed her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feed her frozen/thawed mice, which was what the breeder also fed her. Ball pythons are docile, shy, and not always interested in food. Live feeding can be lethal to the snake if the snake isn't wanting to feed and the prey is wanting to fight, especially if the prey is a bigger rat. The prey items are humanely killed and then I thaw them, warm them up to a body temperature without cooking them, and then feed to Melusina. I also feed her in her enclosure, there is no need to move a snake to a different tank to feed them. This way the snake isn't stressed out from being somewhere else. Feeding in the enclosure won't cause "cage aggression" and won't train your snake to think you hand is food every time you open the cage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few more things: you can also apparently &lt;a href="https://ball-pythons.net/forums/showthread.php?139156-Vypyrz-Tub-Set-Up-The-Basics-*DUW*"&gt;use sterilite or rubbermaid bins as snake enclosures&lt;/a&gt;, they hold heat and humidity better than glass tanks, and you can do pretty much the same set up, with some accomodations for making sure the under tank heaters don't melt the plastic. You use a soldering iron to put some holes in the side, and make sure it has secure clips to keep the lid on. If it doesn't, you can use luggage thing ma bobs to keep it closed. The draw back is you don't have the crystal clear view of your snake. It's cheap though! The PVC enclosures I talked about earlier have the crystal clear view of glass, and the heat/humidity retention of bins. Some of the links that I saw posted over and over again in reddit were really helpful to me, and they might be helpful to you too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://reptimes.com/ball-pythons-the-basics-and-then-some/"&gt;The Basics and Then Some&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://reptimes.com/ball-pythons-common-problems/"&gt;Ball Python Common Problems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://reptimes.com/ball-pythons-feeding/"&gt;Ball Pythons Feeding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've sure learned a lot about snake keeping, and I hope if you have the means, you go for the PVC enclosures, but if you are like me and already have all the stuff for a glass tank, hopefully this can help you get a good set up until you can afford to make a change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh…and about my partner that is terrified of snakes? Totally in love with Melusina now &amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cover Reveal!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/Cover-Reveal/"/>
    <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog/Cover-Reveal/</id>
    <published>2017-01-24T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-01-25T18:27:19-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dax Murray</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's here! The cover for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01MS9NU7F/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1484938920&amp;amp;sr=1-1"&gt;The Resignation Letter&lt;/a&gt; !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/ResignationLetterCover-01.jpg" alt="cover image: a white woman in a gown reclines on a chaise lounge, while a black woman stands in front of scientific tools looking into a magical orb" style="max-width:100%;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Isn't it &lt;em&gt;gorgeous&lt;/em&gt;? &lt;a href="https://juneberrydesign.myportfolio.com/"&gt;Louisa of Juneberry Designs&lt;/a&gt; did a fabulous job getting the look and feel of the characters, and setting up the world, too. Seriously, you should chat with Louisa if you need a cool cover for your books! Having a cover makes it feel much more exciting as the release date draws near! Today for a brief moment the book was in the top rankings on Kindle in several categories. Specifically, in the #1 spot for Kindle Store -&amp;gt; Kindle Short Reads -&amp;gt; 30 Minutes (12 - 21 pages -&amp;gt; LGBT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/kindle_rankings_01_25_17.jpeg" alt="Kindle rankings, #1 in Shorts LGBT, #6 in Science Fiction and Fantasy, and #18 in Literature and Fiction" style="max-width:100%;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've also gotten an advance &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1888708702?book_show_action=true"&gt;review on Goodreads&lt;/a&gt; and I hope y'all will take the time to read and review!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;"…all of the prose is beautifully written and overall, this is a pleasure to read."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've got a novella in the works right now, and hope to get it published before summer (before I will officially be consummed by &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy XIV: Stormblood&lt;/em&gt;). It's one of those dreaded Fairy Tale Retellings. Of course, my version is going to be full of queer people and won't be all white people. I also wanted to send a shout out to someone I forgot to mention in my last post! I wanted to thank Erin Lynn Jeffreys Hodges, who provided a lot of technical and technology related assistance, as well as cheerleading and pom pom waving! Thanks, Erin!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Resignation Letter Announcement and Miscellany</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/The-Resignation-Letter-Announcement/"/>
    <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog/The-Resignation-Letter-Announcement/</id>
    <published>2017-01-19T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-01-20T14:34:08-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dax Murray</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Big news! I am publishing a short story as a Kindle Select ebook! It is titled &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01MS9NU7F/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1484938920&amp;amp;sr=1-1"&gt;The Resignation Letter&lt;/a&gt;, a fantasy story about class, war, love, magic, and tough choices. You can add it to your TBR on &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/33955963-the-resignation-letter?from_search=true"&gt;goodreads&lt;/a&gt;. I've been working on this short story for awhile, and would like to thank &lt;a href="http://www.kathowardbooks.com/"&gt;Kat Howard&lt;/a&gt; for her editing on some of my initial drafts, and &lt;a href="https://juneberrydesign.myportfolio.com/"&gt;Louisa of Juneberry Designs&lt;/a&gt; for the fantastic cover. I'd also like to thank my paramours for their support, and for encouraging me with squees as they read drafts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is hopefully the first of many queer short stories that I plan on publishing in ebook format. For now, you can pre-order the book on Amazon. (Please note the placeholder cover should be gone soon, and the fabulous cover should take it's place!) The long and the short of the story is queer in a fantasy setting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a more technical note, you may have noticed I haven't reviewed a book here in awhile. I was busy working as a software engineer at the Democratic National Committee, which was a really intense job with really long hours! While I had some time to read here and there, it wasn't as much as I usually have, so no time to review.  I hope to maybe do some back-log reviewing in the coming weeks. Also, I may still blog here about code occassionally, but most of my coding stuffy is being moved to &lt;a href="http://dax.codes"&gt;dax.codes&lt;/a&gt;, so here should be mostly feminism and books. You can also find more of my cats now at &lt;a href="http://dax.cat"&gt;dax.cat&lt;/a&gt;. MY CATS ARE WEBSCALE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last detail: I came out as genderqueer, and I am in the process of changing my name. I go by Dax now, you might find some references throughout this site to my old name still, or links to accounts of mine I still haven't changed to reflect my new name. Changing names is a lot of work and a lot of time. Forgive these brief discrepencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solidarity!&lt;br /&gt;
Dax&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Review: The Insurrectionist and the Empress Who Reigns Over Time by Benjanun Sriduangkaew</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/Review-The-Insurrectionist-And-The-Empress-Who-Reigns-Over-Time/"/>
    <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog/Review-The-Insurrectionist-And-The-Empress-Who-Reigns-Over-Time/</id>
    <published>2015-09-16T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-12-29T10:50:39-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dax Murray</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This short story is available for free on Beneath the Ceaseless Sky's website. You can also pay for it on Amazon so you can read it on your Kindle. I did the latter because 1.) It's so good you should support it financially and 2.) I prefer e-ink to backlit screens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"The Insurrectionist and the Empress Who Reigns Over Time" was written specifically to show you can have bad things happen to people, but not make it about the bad things happening because the characters are queer. There is a pattern in fiction, television, movies, where many queer people are shown as so good and pure, by virtue of being queer, that bad things must happen to them to show how cruely the world treats them. They are "too good for this sinful earth" or the authorial intent is to showcase how bad homophobia, biphobia and transphobia are. For me, and others, fiction is an escape from this world. Benjanun Sriduangkaew tweeted out that she intended to show that the bad acts that happen to characters can happen for reasons that are not tied to their sexuality or gender, and that those same characters can also have happy endings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel that "Insurrectionist" accomplished this goal. Benjanun Sriduangkaew did an excellent job of creating a world that felt huge, but not giving the reader the long, rambling history of the world, all of its people, and what the cook makes at every meal. True, this is a short story, so that is the goal. But all of the characters felt real, and while you might not know what happened in some distant past to make them the way they are today, you had enough context to know that their behavior was not arbitrary, and based on plot necessity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Insurrectionist" is the story of a woman who leads uprisings against current governments by working to make rebellions look natural, she uses words and speeches to change the opinions of people. Her greatest gift is her ability to bend words. One day, however, her luck runs out. She is captured, her mouth sewn shut, and imprisoned by an Empress from a kingdom near the one she'd just conquered. The Empress, as the  reader may have guessed, has her own unique abilities. She can move time, and wishes to change a key event. As the Insurrectionist and the Empress figure out how they might be useful to each other, they also figure out they are also attracted to each other. At the end, they find a solution that satisfyingly resolves both of their inner conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This short story is not just noteworthy for having two women who are attracted to women as the main characters. The Empress has two mothers, one assumes from the terms that her one mothers is a trans woman, and the other a cis woman. It was incredibly normal to all of the characters involved. Of course the Empress had a giving-mother, and a bearing-mother. Of course that is a normal family structure. It's also evident that the Empress's current situation, her current emotions and thoughts, are not the result of bad parenting or the result of having a unique-to-the-reader family structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I believe this is the best short story I've read so far in 2015. The writing is beautiful, some beautiful child of poetry and prose. The pacing is perfect for a story about displacement in time, and the pacing served to further that sense of displacement that the Insurrectionist feels. The characters were real and experienced loss and tragedy in the their lives, but never was that loss inextricably tied to their sexuality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read this short story if you are a human with a soul. Don't read this short story if you are a a huge transphobe.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Review: Witches and Wolves by Kelly D. Smith</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/Review-Witches-and-Wolves/"/>
    <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog/Review-Witches-and-Wolves/</id>
    <published>2015-09-15T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-12-29T10:50:39-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dax Murray</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I received an ARC copy of 'Witches and Wolves' from NetGalley in exchange for an honest review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;'Witches and Wolves' was a fun novella about learning to be yourself and falling in love. The story focuses on Tory, a witch who lives in the wood to get away from the city life; Tory's ex-boyfriend, a werewolf who also enjoys the seclusion of the woods; and Gee, a young woman who is new to being a werewolf. Gee is just learning how to control her wolf, and finds herself on Tory's doorstep one night. With the help of her new friends, she learns how to embrace who she is, and also finds herself falling for Tory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought this story was well paced, and the contrast between the external conflicts and the internal conflicts worked to highlight and enhance the inner struggles Gee was going through. I also appreciated that the potential love triangles were not those of most fiction today, and the bisexuality of Tory was not a point of contention for anyone. It's really refreshing to have a bisexual character who is allowed to be human, and isn't subjected to doubt or mistrust from any potential, new, or former lover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed the world-building, too. I felt there was enough details to get a sense of the world without being bogged down in unnecessary backstory or long pages of history. I got enough backstory for the world to know what was relavant to the plot, and a few additional tidbits to make the world of witches, werewolves, and werewolf hunters seem real, interesting, and detailed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through and through, this was a romance story. There was a side plot to solidify the relationship between Gee and Tory, and I enjoyed it. My criticisms would be the length, as I thought it was a bit too short. I would have liked to have a few more intimate scenes between the two of them (not intimate in terms of sexy times, but a few more touching moments).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read this book if you like werewolves and witches falling in love. Don't read this book if you are a fan of the "Bury your gays" trope, and "bisexuals don't exist" tropes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
