<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Dax Murray</title>
  <subtitle>Books. Coding. Feminism. (Cats.)</subtitle>
  <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog</id>
  <link href="http://daxmurray.com/blog"/>
  <link href="http://daxmurray.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2018-05-02T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Dax Murray</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Adding and enforcing SSL / HTTPS  to Your Custom Domain Github Pages for free</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/Adding-SSL-To-GitHub-Pages/"/>
    <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog/Adding-SSL-To-GitHub-Pages/</id>
    <published>2018-05-02T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-04T14:22:09-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dax Murray</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My dayjob involves writing a lot of backend code, and I have written most of the code used on this website. I host it on GitHub Pages with a custom domain. Until May 1, I could not use HTTPS on here. It wasn't such a con when I first started this, but Google now prioritizes SSL encrypted sites and gives big huge warnings on many browsers about forms on non-HTTPS sites. So this meant either using something like CloudFlare CDN or moving to something like Netlify. As I am sure you understand, this site is mostly held together with shoestring and paperclips and do you think I want to spend a day sorting through DNS records for a domain I haven't touched in…a long time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But GitHub has announced you can now have HTTPS enforced on custom domains! However, getting it to work took the better part of a very late night. Their docs on it aren't very clear. It should be straightforward as clicking "Enforce HTTPS" in the repo settings for repos and pages made after today, but if you have an older one you want to turn HTTPS on for, follow this guide!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.) Go to the settings for the repo you are using. There's a gear symbol, and clicking on it should take you there. Towards the middle is the settings for GitHub Pages. There's a form input called "Custom Domain." This should be where you've already entered your custom domain. You want to delete it. Yes, delete it. Empty the text field and hit "Save". I know, scary. Don't worry, we will add it back later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.) Right below that is a checkbox labeled "Enforce HTTPS". It will have been grayed out and unclickable before you deleted the custom domain. Now that it isn't, check the box!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3.) The fancy new HTTPS comes with new IP addresses. So you want to go to your DNS provider and update the IPs. The old ones still work, but you can't get a cool SSL cert with them. I tried. &lt;a href="https://help.github.com/articles/setting-up-an-apex-domain/#configuring-a-records-with-your-dns-provider"&gt;You can find the new IP addresses here&lt;/a&gt;. Make sure to add them all as &lt;code&gt;A&lt;/code&gt; with a host name of &lt;code&gt;@&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4.) Wait. You're gonna be waiting a bit. You are waiting for two things: a.) Your GH Page to get an SSL certificate, b.) the new IP addresses in your DNS to propagate. I periodically checked with a DNS propagation tracker and when a decent amount of them had the new IP addresses, I moved on to the next step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5.) Add back in your custom domain on your GH Pages settings and hit 'save'. If everything worked, the "Enforce HTTPS" setting should remain checked! If something is wrong, you might get the error "Not yet available for your site because the certificate has not finished being issued." This error means you didn't wait long enough for GH to create your SSL cert. Delete the custom domain and wait some more. If it goes back to being grayed out, it means you didn't wait long enough for the new IPs to propagate. Delete the custom domain from your GH pages and wait some more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's it!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Best Books For Writers of Fantasy</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/The-Best-Books-For-Writers-Fantasy/"/>
    <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog/The-Best-Books-For-Writers-Fantasy/</id>
    <published>2018-04-11T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2018-04-12T19:12:55-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dax Murray</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of books that one can find on how to be a better writer. Dean Koontz and Stephen King have both written such books. You can read a dozen books on craft and still walk away with nothing, though. I have tried to select books that I try to always have on my shelf or near me when I am at certain parts of the process. Going into this exercise, I thought I would end up selecting a lot of the books I read in college for my creative writing minor, but none of them made the cut. Instead, I have books that I learned about all within the last year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://smile.amazon.com/Emotion-Thesaurus-Writers-Character-Expression/dp/1475004958/"&gt;The Emotions Thesaurus&lt;/a&gt; So many people will tell you “show, don’t tell.” Very few people will give you concrete examples of how to actually do this. This is the book you need when it comes to “showing” how your characters are feeling. It is arranged alphabetical by emotion, with examples of how to convey that emotion with facial expressions, body language, and many other physical cues. There’s an index in the back so you can quickly find the emotion you are struggling to convey. I find this particularly useful for my “strong silent type” characters, the ones who would rather throw a punch than talk, and for my “shy quiet type” characters who would rather melt into the wall than have to talk to someone they are unfamiliar with (gosh, self, &lt;em&gt;@ me next time!&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.) &lt;a href="https://smile.amazon.com/Positive-Trait-Thesaurus-Character-Attributes/dp/0989772519/"&gt;The Positive Traits Thesaurus&lt;/a&gt; I love to have this book (and the next one!) beside me when I am in the planning stages. I have a rough idea of the characters personalities, but being able to pull up the two page spread on “Perceptive” and instantly have a list of possible reason a character might be perceptive, some of the challenges a perceptive person might encounter, and which personalities they might clash with? It is awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3.) &lt;a href="https://smile.amazon.com/Negative-Trait-Thesaurus-Writers-Character/dp/0989772500/"&gt;The Negative Traits Thesaurus&lt;/a&gt; - Everything I said about the previous one, but for flaws. It’s not just good for trying to dig into your villains backstory, but also trying to figure out how to really stress out your main character. Your main character is disorganized? This book gives meaty examples of how this might totally ruin your MC’s plans and land them two steps back instead of one step forward. My favorite part of this book is “traits in minor characters that may cause conflict” because oh wow do I love putting my characters into conflict. A disorganized MC’s BFF should be meticulous and responsible, after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authors of these awesome thesauri, Angela Ackerman and Becca Puglisi , have a few more such books, including ones on settings that may be super useful to you if you are building worlds from scratch. I highly recommend all of the books, but really tried to narrow it down to the ones that I thought were essentials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4.) &lt;a href="https://smile.amazon.com/Artful-Edit-Practice-Editing-Yourself/dp/0393332179/"&gt;The Artful Edit&lt;/a&gt; I think this book could be read before you write your first MS, or early on in the initial rounds of edits, but it should absolutely be read. Bell gives great examples of editing, and not so great ones (she picks on &lt;em&gt;The Great Gatsby&lt;/em&gt;, much to my delight). I would say this book is more important and necessary that &lt;em&gt;The Elements of Style&lt;/em&gt; and more applicable as it tailors to today’s editing tastes. Bell dispenses a bevy of tips on how to edit your own work and why you need to. This book has insight from editors, authors, and readers on what does and does not make books, scenes, chapters and all the moving parts of a book work together. This isn’t a book on punctuation, grammar, and syntax; it is a book about making words work together as a whole, and it is written in a rivetting narrative that teaches as it also tells a story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5.) &lt;a href="https://smile.amazon.com/Self-Editing-Fiction-Writers-Second-Yourself/dp/0060545690/"&gt;Self-Editing for Writers&lt;/a&gt; If &lt;em&gt;The Artful Edit&lt;/em&gt; was a love letter to editing, this is a recipe book. Nonetheless, there are many incredible chapters on how to edit various parts of your novel. This one is easier to use while actively editing. Having trouble with editing your dialogue? There’s a chapter for that. I would advise using this book for your final edits, while &lt;em&gt;The Artful Edit&lt;/em&gt; should be used very early on as a guide. The authors of this book both have long histories as editing some of the best fiction currently in print, and that expertise truly shows throughout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6.) &lt;a href="https://smile.amazon.com/Fantasys-Othering-Fetish-Phenderson-Djeli-ebook/dp/B01N9K0ZLL/"&gt;Fantasy’s Othering Fetish&lt;/a&gt; The giant sea creature that occupies every room in every fantasy castle ever written. Speculative fiction has a lot of problems, and even though we have the ability to create infinite universes, we always create the same ones. The same, very white, very European, futures and pasts. We write the same story where the people of color are either absent or monsters, window dressing or props. This book was written with a love for fantasy pulsing through every vein, it is a plea for us to do better, to live up to the promise of the genre. It explores “classics” as well as recent publications, it examines the tropes that started centuries ago in Arthurian legend and persist to this day in mega-franchises that have yearly blockbusters. If you are looking for a book full of the very awful tropes and how to avoid them? This is your book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have other books you think should be on this list? Let me know on &lt;a href="https://www.twitter.com/daxaeterna"&gt;Twitter!&lt;/a&gt;. Don’t forget to sign up for my newsletter, where I share exclusive announcements, host giveaways of new releases, and update you on the latest doings of my cats!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;form action="https://buttondown.email/api/emails/embed-subscribe/dax" method="post" target="popupwindow" onsubmit="window.open('https://buttondown.email/dax', 'popupwindow')" class="embeddable-buttondown-form"&gt;
  &lt;label for="bd-email"&gt;Enter your email&lt;/label&gt;
  &lt;input type="email" name="email" id="bd-email" /&gt;
  &lt;input type="hidden" value="1" name="embed" /&gt;
  &lt;input type="submit" value="Subscribe" /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://buttondown.email" target="_blank"&gt;Powered by Buttondown.&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>So you want to self publish on Kindle: Part Three - Kindle Direct Publishing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/setting-up-a-kindle-preorder/"/>
    <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog/setting-up-a-kindle-preorder/</id>
    <published>2017-12-31T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2018-04-08T13:35:23-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dax Murray</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the second part of a multi-part series on self publishing. This series will cover: writing, editing, beta reading, sensitivity reading, setting up a pre-order, using Kindle Direct Publishing, Kindle Select, NetGalley and other means of getting reviews, and marketing. &lt;a href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/so-you-want-to-self-publish/"&gt;Read part one on writing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/self-publishing-part-two-editing/"&gt;read part two on editing, beta readers and sensitivity readers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few people have asked me several questions on self publishing on Kindle. I've talked to people who want to publish small technical books that, for one reason or another, O'Reilly doesn't want to publish. I've talked to fiction writers who want to publish a novel. I've talked to a lot of people who have thought "I wish I could…" And I want to tell you that you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's a lot of steps, and they do not always have a 'correct' order. But they are achievable and you can determine what order you want them to happen in for a lot of them. There are some cart before the horse problems, but largely, writing is the first step, and hitting publish is the last. Everything between there is a malaise of interlooping and overlapping steps to make the writing publishable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a small power point last April to share at a technical conference with other Rails devs who have small or niche book ideas. I am going to heavily self plagarize from that for this post. So if some of my cat photos look familiar to you, that's why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've been writing stories since I was five. My first one went something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;There once was a cat. The cat loved to eat. The cat loved to nap. The cat loved her human. Her human went to school sometimes. That made the cat sad. But the human always came home. The end.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sure my mother still has the bare book complete with hand drawn illustrations somewhere. I actually minored in creative writing in college, and while most of my classes focused on poetry, the itch for stories never left. I was just as confused and scared by the self-publishing maze as anyone else. I won't lie and say it is easy, but it is definitely easier than you think it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="cover-art"&gt;Cover Art&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to set up a successful pre-order, you will need a cover. If you are artsy and great with Photoshop, you can try to make this on your own. If you are not, you will want to hire someone. This is another place where I suggest not attempting to be frugal. Sometime in the middle of having early readers and editors, you will want to hire this cover artist. I hired &lt;a href="http://www.juneberrydesign.com"&gt;Louisa of Juneberry Design&lt;/a&gt; to make my covers. Look at an artist's portfolio, see what else they have done and if you think they can execute on your vision. Look at other self published books in your genre and find covers you like. Ask the authors who they hired to do their cover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find other books in your genre, the ones that you know are making money, self pub'd or not, and see what elements they use. I know Stephen King is the god of the horror genre, and his covers very prominently display his name. Don't do this. Stephen King could sell books by having nothing &lt;em&gt;but&lt;/em&gt; his name on the cover. You can't. You aren't a 'big name' (yet), so you will want a cover that sells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have chosen an artist, you will want to provide this artist with at least the basic gist of the story, the tone, and the genre. Many genre's have a certain feel or style for their covers. Look at some of the bestsellers in your genre and pass those covers onto your artist, letting them know what you do and do not like about them. This can be very back and forth. The artist will probably send you early drafts or stock art and ask how you feel about it. Be honest. If the artist picks a stock art model that looks nothing like how you imagined the character, let them know. It is sometimes helpful to pass along your own images that you might have grabbed way back when you were making character profiles. They will probably not be able to use those images as they are copyrighted, but they can get a better idea of what you are going for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kindle does have its own cover maker. I do not suggest using this. You want your book to look original, and Kindle only has so many stock photos. There is a saying, "do not judge a book by its cover," but no one actually follows that when it comes to books. A professional looking cover tells a reader that they can expect professional level storytelling. There are numerous examples where this was not true, and yet people still have this assumption. You will not be able to convince them otherwise. Have a professional cover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cost for this can be anywhere from $75 to $300, sometimes more depending on who you are hiring. It is absolutely worth every penny to have a top notch cover. There are people on Fivrr or other freelancing sites that offer these services for $5 to $10. I know this is tempting. But what you will end up with is a cover you could had your cat make by setting her on the keyboard while MS Paint is open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For ebooks, you just need the front cover. If you are going to choose the paperback route as well, you will need a back and spine cover too. Usually you put this together as back, spine, front, left to right. Once you have your final manuscirpt uploaded, you can get the dimensions that you need. At first, I used amazon's cover creator for paperback, choosing to use the ebook cover and just type in my own summary and info on a solid colored back. It didn't turn out that great. So I asked Louisa to design a back / spine for me, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Top in both pictures is the one I asked Louisa to professionally create, bottom is what I tried to do myself with Amazon's paperback cover creator. Note the difference in fonts, and the overall better look of the one Louisa did for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/alofm_cover_comparison1.jpg" alt="two books sitting on top of each other, one with an awesome cover, the other not so much" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 45%;" /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/alofm_cover_comparison2.jpg" alt="two books sitting on top of each other, one with an awesome cover, the other not so much" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 45%;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Louisa gave me back the full cover as an image file. But Amazon wants it as a pdf, and just saving the image as a pdf isn't gonna work. So I opened the cover creator, got the dimensions that Amazon wants, and then followed &lt;a href="http://ryallon.blogspot.com/2012/07/converting-book-cover-for-createspace.html"&gt;the instructions in this tutorial for making a cover for createspace&lt;/a&gt;. The height is going to be 9 inches, but the width wants to take into account the front and back plus the spine - the spine can change depending on how many pages you have. Keep this in mind when making changes to your manuscript - anything that adds or deletes pages will affect your paperback cover dimensions. This tutorial uses Open Office, which is a free suite of software similar to Microsoft Office. I've been using Open Office products since 2009 when I got my first ubuntu machine, so I was already familiar with lots of the tools. The tutorial also says its for Createspace, Amazon owns Createspace, and while this tutorial pre-dates that acquision, it's still a very good tutorial on using Open Office Draw to scale and save your cover as a pdf for Amazon. I would wait until you have your final final final manuscript, plus front copy, a table of contents, back copy, etc, all in one uploaded file before trying to size your paperback cover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are truly in a rush, and you want people to be able to pre-order now, make a small cover that says "COVER COMING SOON." I am getting a little ahead of myself, but once you have your pre-order set up, you will want to get the title on Goodreads. Goodreads archives all versions of a cover except one that says "COVER COMING SOON." You do not want a cheaply made placeholder cover to be in the archives of your Goodreads listing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="description"&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want around 200 words for the description. This should not be a synopsis, this should be the &lt;em&gt;stakes&lt;/em&gt;. There are a few rules when it comes to description writing for fiction: keep named characters to a minimum, don't include sub-plots, end on a question or the stakes. You want to hook the readers here, which is pretty hard to do seeing as there so very many books out there they could also be reading. For non-fiction, you want to tells readers what they will learn, how it will help them, and your authority and expertise on the subject. Regardless of what you are writing, you want to keep the description tight and short. Workshop this with friends, family, colleagues, and even your editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can always change your description later, but you definitely want to get it to a good spot for launch. This is what you would want on your paperbacks back cover, too, if you are doing paperbacks. As I suggested with covers, look for books in your genre and see what they have as their description. Check out both self pubbed and traditionally published. Amazon will show you top books in genres, so use that to read those books descriptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="setting-up-the-pre-order"&gt;Setting up the pre-order&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id="why"&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will get into the ins and outs of pre-release marketing, but the long and the short is that during your pre-release marketing, you want people to be able to pre-order. You want them to be able to click that button while they are thinking about it. They will not remember to check back on release day to get it. Having a ton of pre-orders in will also help your ranks. If you start off with a ton of buys on release day, your book may make it to the top of the pages in Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="how"&gt;How?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you want to navigate to &lt;a href="https://kdp.amazon.com"&gt;https://kdp.amazon.com&lt;/a&gt; and connect it to your regular Amazon Account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/kdp_landing.png" alt="KDP landing page, with links to log in or go to your account and a video tutorial" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 90%;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will want your banking information, a version of your manuscript (does not have to be final), and your cover. Amazon will let indie authors set up pre-orders up to 90 days in advance of release and at least 10 days ahead of release. There might be a temptation to have a shorter pre-order window, but you will want those full three months for reasons I will get to later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Banking and Tax Information&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will want to get your banking and tax information taken care of right away. Amazon pays out via paper checks mailed to you or direct deposits into your account. Thing is, they won't send out a check until you've had at least $100 in sales per market after the first 90 days. A "market" is basically a country or region, there is a US market, a UK market, etc. Some markets are super small and you might only ever get $0.10 from them. In check payment, this means you will probably never see that $0.10. But, you can get that at the end of the month if you have Electronic Funds Transfer enabled. So set this up for direct deposit so you can start getting paid sooner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/kdp_tax_information.png" alt="KDP success prompt saying Tax Info has been updated" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 90%;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="creating-your-book"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Creating your book&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once your tax and banking information are done being entered, you will get to a dashboard called your "Bookshelf" - this is where all of your books will live. To start a new one, just click on the "+"! You can pick the ebook option now, and add paperback later if you decide to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/kdp_dashboard.png" alt="KDP dashboard with a list of books and a + sign to start to create a new one" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 90%;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="ebook-details"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ebook Details&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first part of setting up your book is the details section. Many of these fields are optional, so if they do not apply to your book, you can leave them blank. You do need a language and a title. I picked English, as that is the language my book was written in. My book does not have a subtitle, it is not part of series and therefore does not have a series name or a series number. Yours might!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/kdp_step_1.png" alt="Ebook Details: A language drop down field, book title field, book sub title field, series name and series number fields." style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 90%;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon will also as for edition numbers, I put 1 in here because this is the first edition. Should I make major changes or edits and re-publish, I would add that as edition 2! New cover? Also edition 2!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the author field, you can seriously put (almost) anything here. Don't want to use your legal name? That's cool. Want to use a pen name? Also cool! Amazon will let you have multiple names, too. So if this is your first book and it's about computers, you can use one name, and when you decide to start writing about competitive dog grooming, you can take up another pen name. You can have as many pen names as you want. I'd just steer clear of using something like "J.R.R. Tolkein" for what should be obvious reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contributors fields are if you are compiling an anthology or some other work with a ton of other people involved. I've seen it also used to credit editors (ask first!). You can certainly leave this blank if you don't have anyone else who contributed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also you will need to provide your description. Pictured here is my not so great first stab at a description. It limits you on characters, but do not feel compelled to use every character they offer - keep it around 200 words!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/kdp_step_2.png" alt="Ebook Details: Edition number field, author first and last name fields, contributors drop downs and first and last name fields and description large text field" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 90%;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon then asks that you agree that you have the rights / copyright to your work. If you live in the US, this is pretty easy to do. You can either snail mail yourself a &lt;a href="https://store.usps.com/store/product/shipping-supplies/certified-mail-receipt-P_FORM_3800"&gt;certified mail&lt;/a&gt; print out of your manuscript, or you can email yourself a copy. Anything that puts a date on your work is enough for copyright. In most instances, this will be enough. Big name authors, like J.K. Rowling, get huge amounts of frivolous copyright claims (Rowling had someone after her for 'muggles'), the odds are that you won't be one of those big name authors and therefore will never have to produce huge amounts of evidence of copyright. Select the box, and move on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/kdp_step_3.png" alt="Ebook Details: A radio button input asking to verify that you hold the necessary rights to the works" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 90%;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Age and Grade Range are all optional, if you aren't writing children's books, you can skip these fields. Just a quick note, though. A lot of organizations that attempt to create a rubric for what is appropriate for which ages/grades are incredibly homophobic and transphobic. For example, it has been shown that the MPAA regularly rates content with any sort of queer people in it as "R" even if that queer person never even so much as kisses anyone. Queer people and trans people specifically are not inherently sexual and are therefore not inherently inappropriate for children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/kdp_step_4.png" alt="Book Details: Drop down fields for minimum and maximum age range, and minimum and maximum grade levels" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 90%;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="ebook-content"&gt;&lt;em&gt;eBook Content&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing it will ask you is if you want to DRM your book. As a full time software engineer, I just want to say: DRM is poorly written and shitty software. It doesn't at all protect your book, it is easily cracked, and if it is cracked, you have no recourse. I choose not the DRM my books because &lt;em&gt;it makes them accessible&lt;/em&gt;. DRM may prevent readers from using accessibility software. DRM may prevent them from using their own text-to-speech and more. Amazon DRM has also been found to further forced-obsolescence, wherein Amazon will attempt to get users to upgrade their device by making older devices no longer support some DRM'd content. A lot of older Kindles had better text-to-speech than the current ones. I don't want my readers to have to fight to read my book. So I don't use DRM. This also means that someone can buy my book on Amazon and read it on their Nook. Or on any other device that is best suited for them. It's a very important thing for me, but it may not be for you. Select which ever option you feel best about after doing your research on DRM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most confusing part! ISBN's! If you are doing ebook only, you don't need one. Really. For real. &lt;em&gt;But what if I want it on Goodreads?!&lt;/em&gt; Amazon will give you an ASIN, which Goodreads accepts and with that ASIN GR will be able to port in information about your book! If you decide to also do Paperback, Amazon will give you one for free. But really, you don't need one. If you want ebook only and really want an ISBN, you can pay $250 for one, or $1000 for 1000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For "Publisher," you can leave it blank. It will display in store as Amazon Digital Services. You can also set up your own small press which will only publish your works and put that in there, too. It's your call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/kdp_step_5.png" alt="Ebook Content: text fields for ISBN and Publisher" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 90%;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will ask you to upload your manuscript and your cover. It will have a previewer, and you should be able to download it too. I highly suggest downloading it and viewing it on some of your own reading devices! I also recommend asking someone else to do the same! Download it and email it to someone you trust to give an honest look over of it. I also use Calibre to convert my file into other formats and preview it there, too. Even after a zillion times of me looking it over, and others looking it over, I still find weird formatting errors sometimes. Make sure your manuscript has any title pages, copyright pages, dedications, etc that you want. I would suggest picking up a paperback and flipping through each of the first set of pages to see what all is where and when. Hard page breaks, not just hitting 'enter' until you get to a new page, are your friend. Look up how to use hard page breaks in your text editor of choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="ebook-pricing"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ebook Pricing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can get a bit confusing - you have two price options in Kindle, either &lt;em&gt;Kindle Select&lt;/em&gt; prices, or non- &lt;em&gt;Kindle Select&lt;/em&gt; prices. &lt;em&gt;Kindle Select&lt;/em&gt; means you will not publish your works anywhere else for sale. No iBooks. No nook. No SmashWords. No PDF on your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;_Why would I agree to that?!?!?!?!?_&lt;/em&gt;
 - Better royalties.&lt;br /&gt;
 - Your book goes on Kindle Unlimited, and you get paid when someone borrows it.&lt;br /&gt;
 - Your book can into the Kindle Owners Lending Library (this is opt-in), and you get paid when someone borrows it.&lt;br /&gt;
 - You can use Countdown Deals and other promotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose to go this route. So far, I've liked it. I am starting to look at other options, though, such as IngramSpark, which offers wholesale discounts to schools and libraries. For the time being, I am still KDP Select.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KDP Select further breaks down your options as far as how much royalties you get. If you ebook is between $0.99 and $2.98, or over $9.99, you get 35% royalties. If you book is between $2.99 and $9.99, you get 70% royalties. I have my short story, &lt;em&gt;The Resignation Letter&lt;/em&gt;, for $0.99. I only get about $0.30 per purchase, but it is short, and a lot of people don't want to spend $3 on a short story. &lt;em&gt;A Lake of Feathers and Moonbeams&lt;/em&gt; is priced at $4.99, so I get about $4-ish per purchase. A lot of self-pub'd authors with multiple works will price some of them as perma-free or $0.99 as a hook to get readers to purchase the rest of their books. First books in series, shorts, etc - all priced super cheaply to give readers a glance at what they can expect from other works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Countdown Deals&lt;/em&gt; are when your book is temporarily on sale. You can reduce the price of your book once every 90 days and still keep your standard royalty. This means you can price your book at $2.99 and have the 70% royalty, and then for one week lower it to $0.99 and still get 70% of that. This can be a great marketing and promotion tool, especially if you tie it in with social media and blog promotion. It's during these sales that a lot of people will pay for BookBub to feature a book. I'll get more into marketing like this later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For territories, if your work is an original work which no one else has ever published, and which you yourself have never published before, you most likely have world wide rights. Go ahead and select all territories to make your book available globally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/kdp_step_6.png" alt="Ebook Pricing: Radio fields for KDP Select Opt In and Territories" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 90%;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you've set the price, you should be able to set a release date and make it available for pre-order! If you are using a draft manuscript to get the pre-order started, don't forget to upload the final version at least 72 hours before the book is live! Next time I will get in-depth with reviews!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want this series, and other exclusive content, delivered right to your mailbox? I have a newsletter now! &lt;a href="https://buttondown.email/dax/archive/c4598c9a-6ccd-4666-ba15-632f70cc159d"&gt;Checkout the latest issue&lt;/a&gt; and sign up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;form action="https://buttondown.email/api/emails/embed-subscribe/dax" method="post" target="popupwindow" onsubmit="window.open('https://buttondown.email/dax', 'popupwindow')" class="embeddable-buttondown-form"&gt;
  &lt;label for="bd-email"&gt;Enter your email&lt;/label&gt;
  &lt;input type="email" name="email" id="bd-email" /&gt;
  &lt;input type="hidden" value="1" name="embed" /&gt;
  &lt;input type="submit" value="Subscribe" /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://buttondown.email" target="_blank"&gt;Powered by Buttondown.&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Indie Releases of 2017 from Enby and / or Bi Authors - Part 2.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/Bi-And-Or-Enbyof-2017-Part-Two/"/>
    <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog/Bi-And-Or-Enbyof-2017-Part-Two/</id>
    <published>2017-12-23T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2018-04-08T13:35:23-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dax Murray</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you haven't figured it out yet, I am non-binary and I am bi. I also am an indie author. I watched the cool people posting on #nbvember and wanted to specifically write a post about some awesome indie authors who shared my marginalizations. This list is not comprehensive, I sent out a tweet asking people to share their works from this year with me. If I missed you, please let me know and I would be happy to add you. So I present to you, in no particular order, a list of the wonderful works of indie authors who are bi and/or non-binary. I am dividing this up into two parts, because WOW there are a lot and that makes me so happy. &lt;a href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/Bi-And-Or-Enby-Indie-Releases-of-2017/"&gt;Read Part One&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="lindsay-maruska-sandy"&gt;Lindsay Maruska; &lt;em&gt;Sandy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/ellle_em.jpg" alt="" style="max-width: 100%; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.patreon.com/ellemaruska"&gt;Lindsay Maruska&lt;/a&gt;, gender uncertain (she/her for now), is a writer, a mother, a poet, a lapsed historian, academic washout, and a cat person. She is also queer and mentally/physically ill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year Linsay published &lt;a href="https://gumroad.com/l/sandy#"&gt;Advice for Waking Up to the End of the World&lt;/a&gt;, a book of poems about Hurricane Sandy, haunting and gripping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find &lt;a href="https://www.twitter.com/ellle_em"&gt;Lindsay on Twitter @ellle_em&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="lyssa-chiavari-cheerleaders-from-planet-x"&gt;Lyssa Chiavari; &lt;em&gt;Cheerleaders From Planet X&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/lyssachiavari.jpg" alt="Lyssa looking up at the camera, a smile on her face" style="max-width: 100%; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://lyssachiavari.com"&gt;Lyssa Chiavari&lt;/a&gt; is an author of speculative fiction for young adults, including FOURTH WORLD, the first book in a YA sci-fi adventure trilogy set on Mars. She has also written several pieces of short fiction, and is the editor of PERCHANCE TO DREAM, a young adult collection of Shakespeare retellings. Lyssa lives with her family and way too many animals in the woods of Northwest Oregon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, Lyssa Chiavari published &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2AVioFs"&gt;&lt;em&gt;CHEERLEADERS FROM PLANET X&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a f/f YA adventure full of cheerleaders and alien invasion tropes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find Lyssa &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lyssachiavari"&gt;On Twitter @LyssaChiavari&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="a-m-blaushild-good-angel"&gt;A. M. Blaushild; &lt;em&gt;Good Angel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/amblaushild.jpg" alt="A.M. Blaushild smiling with some bird friends" style="max-width: 100%; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://amblaushild.wordpress.com/"&gt;A. M. Blaushild&lt;/a&gt; is a fearless, frivolous fiend with a friendly affection for angels who is currently studying publishing and creative writing at University. 
This year, A.M. released &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2Bu0CZI"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Good Angel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, described as “GOOD OMENS meets FANGIRL,” “an urban fantasy dramedy about good, evil, friendship, and the end of the world.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AMblaushild"&gt;A. M. Blaushild on Twitter @AMblaushild&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="anne-chivon-cottontail-games"&gt;Anne Chivon, &lt;em&gt;Cottontail Games&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/annechivon.jpg" alt="Anne Chivon looking at the camera with a purple bob cut" style="max-width: 100%; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://annechivon.wordpress.com/"&gt;Anne Chivon&lt;/a&gt; thrives off of historical tv series, great fantasy and scifi books, and games. Most of her time is spent writing poetry that holds an element of cute and creepy, and stories about helpful monsters and magic wielding women. She strives to create works for and about the LGBTQIA+ community, as well as being an advocate for normalizing and destimatizing mental illness. 
This year Anne released &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2zgVMgj"&gt;Cottontail Games&lt;/a&gt;, a book of poetry that touches on emotional abuse, eating disorders, gender issues, and mental illness as well as being very sapphic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PeonyWings"&gt;Anne Chivon on Twitter @PeonyWings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="carlo-matos-the-quitters"&gt;Carlo Matos, &lt;em&gt;The Quitters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/carlomatos.jpg" alt="A black and white photo of Carlo looking over his shoulder, superimposed over him is text" style="max-width: 100%; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://carlomatos.blogspot.com/"&gt;Carlo Matos&lt;/a&gt; is a writer, professor, pugilist, rapierist, bisexual, Editor of @CleaverMagazine, and Dad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, Carlo published &lt;a href="http://www.tortoisebooks.com/wholesale/the-quitters"&gt;The Quitters&lt;/a&gt;, “a collection of creative essays explores the beauty and pain embedded in some of our favorite rough-and-tumble pastimes–roller derby, mixed martial arts, and teaching.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CarloMatos46/"&gt;You can find Carlo Matos on Twitter @CarloMatos46&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="dusk-peterson-eternal-dungeon-sweetblood"&gt;Dusk Peterson; &lt;em&gt;Eternal Dungeon: Sweetblood&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/duskpeterson.jpg" alt="a black and white logo of an interlocking d and p" style="max-width: 100%; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://duskpeterson.com/"&gt;Dusk Peterson&lt;/a&gt; (they/them) writes historical speculative fiction with diverse characters: historical fantasy, alternate history, and retrofuture science fiction. Friendship, romantic friendship, and romance often occur in the stories Dusk writes. Dusk currently resides with “several thousand books.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year Dusk published the last volume in the &lt;em&gt;Eternal Dungeon series&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2AWqjCr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sweetblood&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which is an alternate history series set in a nineteenth-century prison and centering bi characters. The omnibus of earlier volumes was a winner in the Rainbow Awards. 
You can find &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/duskpeterson/"&gt;Dusk on Twitter @duskpeterson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="racheline-maltese--erin-mcrae-the-art-of-three"&gt;Racheline Maltese &amp;amp; Erin McRae; &lt;em&gt;The Art of Three&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/rachelinemaltese.png" alt="Racheline Maltese turned slighty to look at the camera" style="max-width: 26.5%; display: inline-block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto" /&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/erinmcrae.jpeg" alt="Erin McRae looking straight ahead, black and white, slightly off center" style="max-width: 50%; display: inline-block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://avian30.com/"&gt;Racheline Maltese&lt;/a&gt; is an award-winning romance author, writer/producer on Tremontaine, does game scripts for Voltage USA. is a SAG-AFTRA performer,  political hobbyist and media analyst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://avian30.com/"&gt;Erin McRae&lt;/a&gt; is a writer and blogger based in Washington, D.C. She has a bachelor’s degree in International Relations from the University of Toronto, and a Master’s degree in International Affairs from American University where she studied the role of social media in the Arab Spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year they co-wrote and published &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2AVbmk6"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Art of Three&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a book that promises “Two men. One woman. No love triangles.” It is a contemporary romance that celebrates families, and farce, in all shapes and sizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/racheline_m/"&gt;Racheline on Twitter @racheline_m&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/erincmcrae"&gt;Erin on Twitter @erincmcrae&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="ts-porter-rescues-and-the-rhyssa"&gt;TS Porter; &lt;em&gt;Rescues and the Rhyssa&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ts-porter.tumblr.com/"&gt;TS Porter&lt;/a&gt; (They/Them) is a writer of science fiction and fantasy, a tiny geek frequently mistaken for a collection of knobbly twigs wearing glasses. When not sleeping, they are usually found obsessively writing or baking sweet delicacies. TS’ physical location and momentum varies, but home is always online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, TS released their first novel, &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2yJVPhf"&gt;Rescues and the Rhyssa&lt;/a&gt;, an epic space opera where unlikely allies must cooperate to rescue royal children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TSPorterAuthor/"&gt;You can find TS on Twitter @TSPorterAuthor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="section"&gt;2018&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you a bi and/or enby indie author who has a book coming out in 2018? &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/forms/YChXyacdf171ntid2"&gt;Let me know!&lt;/a&gt;, I'd love to feature you on my blog!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Indie Releases of 2017 from Enby and / or Bi Authors - Part 1.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/Bi-And-Or-Enby-Indie-Releases-of-2017/"/>
    <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog/Bi-And-Or-Enby-Indie-Releases-of-2017/</id>
    <published>2017-12-15T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2018-04-08T13:35:23-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dax Murray</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you haven't figured it out yet, I am non-binary and I am bi. I also am an indie author. I watched the cool people posting on #nbvember and wanted to specifically write a post about some awesome indie authors who shared my marginalizations. This list is not comprehensive, I sent out a tweet asking people to share their works from this year with me. If I missed you, please let me know and I would be happy to add you. So I present to you, in no particular order, a list of the wonderful works of indie authors who are bi and/or non-binary. I am dividing this up into two parts, because WOW there are a lot and that makes me so happy. Don't forget to &lt;a href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/Bi-And-Or-Enbyof-2017-Part-Two/"&gt;checkout part two!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="melissa-jennings-afterlife"&gt;Melissa Jennings; &lt;em&gt;Afterlife&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/melissa_jennings.JPG" alt="An enby in winter apparel looking back at the camera, in the background there is a grey but lively body of water" style="width: 100%;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.melissajennings.co/"&gt;Melissa Jennings&lt;/a&gt; (they/them) is a bi and non-binary poet lives with their cat, Dora, in the sometimes sunny but always vibrant city of Glasgow, in Scotland. Melissa is currently studying towards an MA in English Literature at the University of Glasgow. They are an avid reader and a writer of many genres - poetry is just the first step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year they released &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2yuO52B"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Afterlife&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a collection of poetry about catharsis, self-love, and self-revolution. Afterlife is a journey from the darkness to the light again, and again, and again. They are also currently and chaotically working on their next poetry collections, &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/35275173-underworld"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Underworld&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36177179-dear-judas"&gt;&lt;em&gt;dear judas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, both expected in 2018. You can find them on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thebookishpoet"&gt;Twitter @thebookishpoet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="roanna-sylver-the-lifeline-signal-stake-sauce"&gt;RoAnna Sylver; &lt;em&gt;The Lifeline Signal&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Stake Sauce&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/roanna_sylver.jpeg" alt="RoAnna Sylver giving the biggest smile ever, with the coolest sunglasses. the air is shimmering" style="max-width: 100%;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.patreon.com/RoAnnaSylver"&gt;RoAnna Sylver&lt;/a&gt; writes unusually hopeful dystopian stories (and now vampire stories) about marginalized heroes actually surviving, triumphing, and rocking really hard. RoAnna is also a singer, blogger, voice actor and artist who lives with family and a small snorking dog, and probably spends too much time playing videogames. The next amazing adventure RoAnna would like is a nap in a pile of bunnies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year RoAnna released the second book in the &lt;em&gt;Chameleon Moon&lt;/em&gt; series, &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2BmfCJ5"&gt;The Lifeline Signal&lt;/a&gt;, a series about the people who are trapped on Parole, a city sealed off from the rest of the world, and their determination to survive a burning city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RoAnna also released the first book in a series about queer vampires, &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2B0xUwL"&gt;Stake Sauce&lt;/a&gt;, centering a punk vampire who doesn’t drink blood, and his new roommate, a former first responder trying to heal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RoAnna has a &lt;a href="http://subscribepage.com/u1v4f6"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; where you can get book updates, early release access, exclusive discounts and giveaways! RoAnna is on Twitter &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RoAnnaSylver"&gt;@RoAnnaSylver&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="b-r-sanders-extraction"&gt;B R Sanders; &lt;em&gt;Extraction&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/brsanders_authorphoto.png" alt="B R Sanders smiling at something just out of frame, and wearing awesome square glasses" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://brsanderswrites.com/"&gt;B R Sanders&lt;/a&gt; (they/them) is a genderqueer writer with disabilities. They write about queer elves, mostly. They live and work in Denver, CO, with their family and two cats. Outside of writing, B has worked as a research psychologist, a labor organizer and a K-12 public education data specialist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year they released &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2yuOL7S"&gt;Extraction (A Tale of Rebellion Book 1)&lt;/a&gt;, a story of lives shaped by hard choices and unforeseen consequences. In &lt;em&gt;Extraction&lt;/em&gt;, a newly minted captain of a rebellion realizes that she is just a pawn in a larger game. When she tries to protect her soldiers, she is forced to decide the course of her future and the future of the elvish rebellion itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href="http://eepurl.com/bgYFjf"&gt;subscribe to B R Sanders Author Newsletter&lt;/a&gt; for more updates on their writing. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/B_R_Sanders"&gt;On Twitter, they live @B_R_Sanders.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="shira-glassman-knit-one-girl-two-eitans-chord-a-lesbian-fairy-trio-for-chanukah"&gt;Shira Glassman; &lt;em&gt;Knit One, Girl Two&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Eitan's Chord: a lesbian fairy trio for Chanukah&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/shira_glassman.jpg" alt="Shira Glassman focused on playing a violin while wearing an awesome floral wreath" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://shiraglassman.wordpress.com/"&gt;Shira Glassman&lt;/a&gt; (she/her) is a bisexual Jewish violinist passionately inspired by German and French opera and Agatha Christie novels. She is a writer of contemporary and fantasy stories. She lives in north central Florida, where the alligators are mostly harmless because they're too lazy to be bothered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year she released &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2kvih8z"&gt;Knit One, Girl Two&lt;/a&gt;, an incredibly cute contemporary romance about a yarn dyer and an artist set in South Florida. There’s also the best cat in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She also released &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2zdKae3"&gt;Eitan's Chord: a lesbian fairy trio for Chanukah&lt;/a&gt;, a short about some adorable Chanukah fairies— Latke, Dreidl, and Menorah— who decide to help an impoverished young couple in fulfilling their Chanukah wishes. As Shira says, this is “spicy” and not suitable for children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find Shira on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ShiraGlassman"&gt;Twitter @ShiraGlassman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="dominique-cyprs-dead-monochrome-doggerel"&gt;Dominique Cyprès; &lt;em&gt;Dead Monochrome Doggerel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/dominique_cypres.jpg" alt="Dominique shown in black and white, wearing spiffy glasses and looking slightly downward" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lunasspecto"&gt;Dominique Cyprès&lt;/a&gt; is an amateur writer, amateur programmer, actual retail wage worker. Agender dad. Dominique Cyprès lives in the Merrimack Valley region of Massachusetts with their two spouses, their child, and two cats. They published their first book of poetry in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year they released &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2kuDWxN"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dead Monochrome Doggerel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a book of poems that occupy a space that borders on the personal and the political, &lt;em&gt;Dead Monochrome Doggerel&lt;/em&gt; places the poet's life, and the contemporary social moment, along the long, murky arc of history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lunasspecto"&gt;Dominique on Twitter @lunasspecto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="sara-taylor-woods-hold-me-down"&gt;Sara Taylor Woods; &lt;em&gt;Hold Me Down&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/sara_taylor_woods.jpg" alt="Sara with her arm propped to the side, looking into the camera. Behind her is a nice nature scene." style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://sarataylorwoods.wordpress.com/"&gt;Sara&lt;/a&gt; writes erotic romance and dark contemporary fantasy. Her stories have been included in romance, erotica, and horror anthologies. When she’s not writing, she’s wrangling her two bouncing dogs, mainlining coffee, or working out. She lives in South Carolina with her husband.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year Sara released &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2yurp2x"&gt;Hold Me Down (Carolina Girls Book 1)&lt;/a&gt;, as Sara describes it, “a standalone romance with a HEA. It contains graphic sexual situations, language, D/s elements (including Daddy play), as well as discussion (but no depiction) of self-harm.” She also released a short story following the events of &lt;em&gt;Hold Me Down&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2CmTUSI"&gt;Fall&lt;/a&gt;. Still has a Happily Ever After, do not fear!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sarataylorwoods"&gt;Sara on Twitter @sarataylorwoods&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="elisabeth--em-hamill-dali"&gt;Elisabeth / E.M. Hamill; &lt;em&gt;Dali&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/emhamil.jpg" alt="E.M.'s face up close, done in brush strokes" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.elisabethhamill.com/"&gt;E.M.&lt;/a&gt; is an award winning author of fantasy and sci fi, a chocoholic, unabashed geek, and a worshipper of caffeine in all its forms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, as E.M. Hamill, she published &lt;a href="http://www.elisabethhamill.com/all-that-entails"&gt;&lt;em&gt;All That Entails,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; a romantic historical short story, in NineStar Press's &lt;em&gt;Beneath the Layers&lt;/em&gt; LGBT Anthology, and  &lt;a href="http://www.elisabethhamill.com/dali"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dalí&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - a full-length science fiction novel published also by Nine Star Press, a small press independent publisher. &lt;em&gt;Dalí&lt;/em&gt; takes place in a dystopian future in which the titular character must save a ton of people while being fresh out of fucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SongMagick"&gt;Elisabeth/E.M Hamill‏ on Twitter @SongMagick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="corey-alexander-building-something-new"&gt;Corey Alexander; &lt;em&gt;Building Something New&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/copy-cropped-alley.jpg" alt="Shot of Corey from waist down, wearing very comfy looking jeans, leaning against a brick wall on a snowey day" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://xanwest.wordpress.com"&gt;Corey Alexander&lt;/a&gt; (they/them) blogs about queerness, disability, kink, trauma, being trans, fat politics &amp;amp; writing. You can find their queer kink erotica &amp;amp; romance under their pen name, Xan West.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, Corey will be releasing a short piece, &lt;em&gt;Building Something New&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2okHM1I"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Big Book of Submission&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, this piece is a kink piece centering a femme trans man &amp;amp; a trans butch. It will be available December 19, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find &lt;a href="https://www.twitter.com/TGStoneButch"&gt;Corey Alexander on Twitter‏ @TGStoneButch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>2017 Awards Eligibility Post</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/Hugo-Nebula-Awards-Elibility-Post/"/>
    <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog/Hugo-Nebula-Awards-Elibility-Post/</id>
    <published>2017-12-04T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2018-04-08T13:35:23-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dax Murray</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I wrote a few things this year! Some of them are eligible for awards. If you've read and enjoyed my works this year, and would like to nominate them for awards, please feel free to do so! As far as I can tell, the following works are eligible for Hugo &amp;amp; Nebula awards in the Novel and Short Story categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But wait, you might be asking, all of the works you released this year are self published! Are they &lt;em&gt;truly&lt;/em&gt; eligible? Yes, they are! According to the Hugo's official rules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Self-published works, e-books, and other “non-traditionally” published works are eligible. There is no restriction requiring works to be published through “traditional” publishers.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here are the relevant rules for the Nebula Awards:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;All works first published in English, in the United States, during the calendar year, in the genres of science fiction, fantasy, or a related fiction genre are eligible for the Nebula Awards® in their respective categories.
        Works first published in English on the Internet or in electronic form during the calendar year shall be treated as though published in the United States.
        Works are eligible whether or not their authors are members of SFWA.
        Works are eligible whether or not they have been previously published outside of the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the categories, "best novel" and "best short story" are described by the Hugos as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Best Novel: Awarded for a science fiction or fantasy story of forty thousand (40,000) words or more.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Best Short Story: Awarded for science fiction or fantasy story of less than seven thousand five hundred (7,500) words.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And by the Nebula Awards as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Short Story: less than 7,500 words;
    Novel: 40,000 words or more.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="novel"&gt;Novel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2hEV8j8"&gt;A Lake of Feathers and Moonbeams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (47,500 words)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For as long as Katya can remember, her partner Ivan, a powerful sorcerer, has given her anything she's ever wanted. Life is simple, until soldiers escorting Princess Yi Zhen enter the magical woods they call home. When Ivan captures the princess and demands Katya watch over her, she reluctantly agrees, entering a dark web of political grudges spanning centuries. Katya soon finds herself falling for the captive princess — and is pretty sure the princess is into her, too. To make matters worse, Yi Zhen is betrothed to a roguish princen who's made it their mission to set her free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As forces rally to rescue Yi Zhen or go to war, Katya must take measure of her own powers and decide what she is willing to sacrifice. Will she retreat to the safety of what's familiar or give up everything she knows to spread her wings and fly?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Lake of Feathers and Moonbeams&lt;/em&gt; was published in ebook and paperback on October 27, 2017. It is #ownvoices for bisexuality, anxiety, polyamory, and being non-binary. It was edited by &lt;a href="http://www.clearingblocksediting.com/"&gt;Jen Anderson of Clearing Blocks Editing&lt;/a&gt; and the cover art was created by &lt;a href="https://juneberrydesign.myportfolio.com/"&gt;Louisa Smith of Juneberry Design&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="short-story"&gt;Short Story&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2hEV8j8"&gt;The Resignation Letter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
(5,000 words)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amalthea has always gone against the rules, applying to the Academy of Mages first, and then studying forbidden magic when accepted. But when she finds her lover, the Empress, asking her to break the rules of her own ethics, she must decide for herself what is more important to her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Resignation Letter&lt;/em&gt; was published in ebook format on January 30, 2017. It is #ownvoices for bisexuality. It was edited by &lt;a href="http://www.kathowardbooks.com/editing/"&gt;Kat Howard&lt;/a&gt; and the cover art was created by &lt;a href="https://juneberrydesign.myportfolio.com/"&gt;Louisa Smith of Juneberry Design&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
