<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Dax Murray</title>
  <subtitle>Books. Coding. Feminism. (Cats.)</subtitle>
  <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog</id>
  <link href="http://daxmurray.com/blog"/>
  <link href="http://daxmurray.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-11-28T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Dax Murray</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>So you want to self publish on Kindle: Part Two - Editing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/self-publishing-part-two-editing/"/>
    <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog/self-publishing-part-two-editing/</id>
    <published>2017-11-28T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-29T17:21:17-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dax Murray</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the second part of a multi-part series on self publishing. This series will cover: writing, editing, beta reading, sensitivity reading, setting up a pre-order, using Kindle Direct Publishing, Kindle Select, NetGalley and other means of getting reviews, and marketing. &lt;a href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/so-you-want-to-self-publish/"&gt;Read part one&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few people have asked me several questions on self publishing on Kindle. I've talked to people who want to publish small technical books that, for one reason or another, O'Reilly doesn't want to publish. I've talked to fiction writers who want to publish a novel. I've talked to a lot of people who have thought "I wish I could…" And I want to tell you that you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's a lot of steps, and they do not always have a 'correct' order. But they are achievable and you can determine what order you want them to happen in for a lot of them. There are some cart before the horse problems, but largely, writing is the first step, and hitting publish is the last. Everything between there is a malaise of interlooping and overlapping steps to make the writing publishable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a small power point last April to share at a technical conference with other Rails devs who have small or niche book ideas. I am going to heavily self plagiarize from that for this post. So if some of my cat photos look familiar to you, that's why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've been writing stories since I was five. My first one went something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;There once was a cat. The cat loved to eat. The cat loved to nap. The cat loved her human. Her human went to school sometimes. That made the cat sad. But the human always came home. The end.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sure my mother still has the bare book complete with hand drawn illustrations somewhere. I actually minored in creative writing in college, and while most of my classes focused on poetry, the itch for stories never left. I was just as confused and scared by the self-publishing maze as anyone else. I won't lie and say it is easy, but it is definitely easier than you think it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="editing-beta-readers-sensitivity-reading"&gt;Editing, Beta Readers, Sensitivity Reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have written the last word. You've done it, you've written a book. First, take a second to congratulate yourself. Celebrate with a cookie, or chocolate, or cake, or a milkshake, or fries and a hamburger - anyway you celebrate big achievements, do that now! Scream or jump or pump your fists. You have reached a goal and you should be proud of that. Regardless of how you approach the rest of this process, know that you should be proud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would recommend, before we get into the various types of editing and reading, that you take at least a week off from working on your manuscript. Set it down and do not touch it for as long as you can. Some people take a week, some people take a month. Find something else that recharges and energizes you. For me, that was a month away to play &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy XIV: Stormblood&lt;/em&gt;. Wow, was it worth it. I actually took a week off of work, too, to play at the launch of the expansion. Having this time away from my manuscript and work allowed me to come back to the manuscript with fresh eyes, while also allowing me to liberate Doma and Ala Mhigo from the clutches of the Garlean Empire and make tons of amazing friends along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began doing my own set of edits. I would definitely say you should do at least on round of self editing before you hand it off to anyone else. I found typos, inconsistencies, bad grammar, bad punctuation, and a ton more. When I finished my manuscript in June I had 52,000 words. I did not want this story to be more than 45,000 words. After coming back from my time away, I was able to easily find places where repetition was hampering the pace. I was able to cut the story down to 45,000. Long rambling passages that did not serve the plot were cut. The first 2,000 words of the story were actually cut. The original words I had written back in January were gone. Go into this first round with a very critical eye. Do not be afraid to slash out entire paragraphs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, now what? Now comes the process of making your work even better. There's a lot of steps between now and hitting publish, and many of them can be done simultaneously or in many different orders. It is up to you how you want to order the next few steps - there is no universal order you must follow. Whatever you think will work best for you and your work flow is what you should follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="sensitivity-readers"&gt;Sensitivity Readers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sensitivity readers are people who are aware of what tropes, stereotypes, and pitfalls characters might fall into from a certain background. If you are not queer, and one of your characters is queer, you might want to find someone who is queer to point out where you might accidentally be writing into a bad stereotype. The example I gave in the first part of this series, "Bury You Gays," would be an example. This is usually a paid service. &lt;a href="http://writeinthemargins.org/sensitivity-readers/"&gt;Writing in the Margins&lt;/a&gt; has a large database of people who are willing to do sensitivity readings and for what groups they can read for. It would be a good to find these people when you finish your manuscript so you can book them for the time that will work best for both of you. Rates for these services can vary from a system of cost per word or cost per hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might not have the money up front to pay these services. Some of them will do skill exchanges (I will, for example). You ask them to read for you and in exchange you can do some art for them, or provide some code for their website, or be a sensitivity reader for them later on. Some of them might offer payment plans. But I absolutely need to stress that this is work. They will point out harmful tropes and write an edit letter explaining what they liked and didn't like. When I do sensitivity reading, I use comments to point out passages or phrases that don't quite work. Some others might compile a document with those quotes, page numbers, and why the didn't work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a sensitivity reader is not a 100% guarantee that your work will be free of harmful tropes. No two queer people have the exact same experiences, what one reader might view as fine, another can point out ways in which it is harmful. For example, there are queer people who did not end up homeless after coming out, and there are many who did. If you ask someone who had a loving and supportive family to do a read for a novel where the queer character ends up homeless, you might not be getting the best gauge on if you are using harmful tropes. When you ask a reader, include a little bit of detail or background so they can get a better sense on if they would be best. Sometimes they might even provide you a recommendation for someone who would be better suited. Most sensitivity readers will ask that you not use their name as a shield if someone finds your work hurtful. In this event, apologize and strive to do better in the future. You might ask, on your end, that the sensitivity reader not talk about the details of your book until it comes out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people will have sensitivity readers early on in the process, after the first self-edit. This way if things need to be structurally changed to avoid a harmful trope, those changes can be made before anyone else sees the work. It can be difficult to have to change tracks after you've had everyone else give input. Some people want to do this last, as they want the story to be in as final a state as it can be so they are only making small tweaks. Some people do it somewhere in between. Do whatever you feel is best for your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="beta-readers"&gt;Beta Readers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beta readers are people commenting on the overall arch of your work. They give feedback like "this part confused me" or "I don't know if I quite got what was going on here" or "this pulled me out of the story." They are not editors and their comments will probably be more sparse. These are usually people you know personally but trust to not sugarcoat. Friends, family, and people in your writing group are usually beta readers.They give you a glimpse into how a reader might respond to your story. If you have written a tear-jerking scene and they get to it and are laughing, you know there is a disconnect between what you intended and what readers read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will want to try to explain to them the parts that they misunderstood. Don't. Do not try to explain to them what they didn't get. You won't be able to do that for a regular reader. Instead, tweak what you have written. Take a good look and try to figure out what got lost between your head and the keyboard. Ask them questions - "why did you find this funny?" - and take that feedback with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beta Readers can sometimes fill in the shoes of sensitivity readers. If one of your beta readers shares a marginalization with one of your characters, they can point out harmful bits, but do not expect them to provide the kind of thoroughness of a proper sensitivity reader. If you do beta reading before sensitivity reading, you might be able to make quick fixes to be on the right track when you send it to a sensitivity reader. Likewise, if you do a sensitivity read first, a beta reader might be able to affirm that you did the work to get your characters out of bad tropes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should compensate your beta readers in some capacity. Friends and family might be willing to do it for free, but offer them a small gift card or offer to take them out to dinner. There are professional beta readers - people who you do not know who list their services on freelancing sites. It might be useful to employ at least one of these people to get parallax between what friends and family are saying. Useful, but not necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="editing"&gt;Editing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The elephant in the room. The large, and sometimes expensive, elephant. Resist the urge to say "I do not think I need one, I was an English major/minor." Resist the urge to say "the edits I did myself are good enough." Both are false. You absolutely need an editor. There are mistakes that you will not be able to see because you wrote it. Mistakes that your brain slides over because it knows what you meant and will substitute in your intent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does an editor do? It depends. There are several different kinds of editors. I highly recommend reading &lt;a href="http://www.clearingblocksediting.com/what-type-of-editing-do-you-need/"&gt;this article on the kinds of editing&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/clearing_blocks"&gt;Jen Anderson&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="http://www.clearingblocksediting.com/"&gt;Clearing Blocks Editing&lt;/a&gt;. The long and the short is that there are copy edits, line edits (sometimes called developmental editing), and proof reading. Some editors will offer all three for one price, others excel at one or two and can refer out for the others. As someone who is self-publishing, I get that this looks expensive. Figure out which of those you are pretty good at yourself, and hire someone to do at least one of the others. If you have the cash, hire someone to do all three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will want to start booking this in advance. Many editors book up months in advance. I reached out to Jen in the early spring for a slot in August. Like beta reading and sensitivity reading, it is ok to book this before you have your manuscript done, so long as you know you will finish it in time. Any good editor will before a sample edit for you for free. You want to take a few pages of your roughest work and send it to them. Fight the urge to send them your best pages, you want them to get an honest look at your work and be able to gauge accurately how long it will take them. You also want to see what the best they can do is. Take that sample edit and check the comments and changes against what you are intending. If you do not think the editor will help you keep your voice and your vision, do not book them. I felt that Jen Anderson understood what I was trying to achieve, and she had a shared goal of making sure my work and writing were the best they could be for that vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could take anywhere from a week to two months for an editor to go through the whole manuscript. It all depends on how long your work is, if the editor has a day job, and how much improvement your manuscript needs. The editor should be able to give you an estimate of how long it will take and how much it will cost after completing the sample edit and you disclosing what you think the word count will be when you turn it in to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cost can be anywhere from $75 to over $1000. This depends on how good your manuscript is when you hand it over, how long it is, and how long it will take the editor to complete it. Many editors will ask for a deposit when you first book, and the rest of the fee will be invoiced after the edited manuscript is sent back to you. This is probably not a place that you can bargain or skill trade. Some editors, however, will do discounts if you are a marginalized writer. Many editors will also offer discounted prices for repeat clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand that you might not have a huge amount of money pour into this upfront. But bad reviews are even more costly. Amazon reviewers, generally speaking, will only tolerate a few typos before leaving a one star review. No matter how stellar your later works are, readers will find those old reviews from the days you hastily posted an un-edited manuscript online. Not having your first work professionally edited can sabotage your sales for years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People might want to do this edit first, before they send it to readers so that the readers will be able to focus just on the experience, rather than being pulled out of the story by a typo or a clumsy sentence. Some people might want to do it last so that there are no big changes that might introduce new paragraphs or changes in plot after being pointed out by readers. Know your strengths and weakness and figure out the order that works best for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting all of these moving parts to line up can be a challenge. I've been a beta reader where the author sends the same google doc link to ten beta readers, and asks that we all leave comments. This author gave the option of leaving comments anonymously or under our google account. This meant that the author did not have to deal with ten different sets of comments in separate documents. Something like this might work well for you for beta readers or sensitivity readers. For working with editors, if you are working with more than one, to not do them synchronously. Send it to one editor, make changes, send to the next. Find some sort of versioning system so you can keep track of which file is which.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have all the comments from all the different readers back, and you have integrated their suggestions, it's time to start compiling a finished draft for publication. I will discuss how to set up on KDP (Kindle Direct Publishing), including formatting, ISBN questions, and questions about cover art in the next instalment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ping me on &lt;a href="https://www.twitter.com/DaxAeterna"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; if you have questions about any of the steps outlined here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want the next issue in your inbox? Sign up for my newsletter!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;form action="https://buttondown.email/api/emails/embed-subscribe/dax" method="post" target="popupwindow" onsubmit="window.open('https://buttondown.email/dax', 'popupwindow')" class="embeddable-buttondown-form"&gt;
  &lt;label for="bd-email"&gt;Enter your email&lt;/label&gt;
  &lt;input type="email" name="email" id="bd-email" /&gt;
  &lt;input type="hidden" value="1" name="embed" /&gt;
  &lt;input type="submit" value="Subscribe" /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://buttondown.email" target="_blank"&gt;Powered by Buttondown.&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>So you want to self publish on Kindle</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/so-you-want-to-self-publish/"/>
    <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog/so-you-want-to-self-publish/</id>
    <published>2017-11-22T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-23T13:04:26-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dax Murray</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the first part of a multi-part series on self publishing. This series will cover: writing, editing, beta reading, sensitivity reading, setting up a pre-order, using Kindle Direct Publishing, Kindle Select, NetGalley and other means of getting reviews, and marketing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few people have asked me several questions on self publishing on Kindle. I've talked to people who want to publish small technical books that, for one reason or another, O'Reilly doesn't want to publish. I've talked to fiction writers who want to publish a novel. I've talked to a lot of people who have thought "I wish I could…" And I want to tell you that you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's a lot of steps, and they do not always have a 'correct' order. But they are achievable and you can determine what order you want them to happen in for a lot of them. There are some cart before the horse problems, but largely, writing is the first step, and hitting publish is the last. Everything between there is a malaise of interlooping and overlapping steps to make the writing publishable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a small power point last April to share at a technical conference with other Rails devs who have small or niche book ideas. I am going to heavily self plagarize from that for this post. So if some of my cat photos look familiar to you, that's why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've been writing stories since I was five. My first one went something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;There once was a cat. The cat loved to eat. The cat loved to nap. The cat loved her human. Her human went to school sometimes. That made the cat sad. But the human always came home. The end.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sure my mother still has the bare book complete with hand drawn illustrations somewhere. I actually minored in creative writing in college, and while most of my classes focused on poetry, the itch for stories never left. I was just as confused and scared by the self-publishing maze as anyone else. I won't lie and say it is easy, but it is definitely easier than you think it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="part-one-writing"&gt;Part One: Writing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The writing is the hardest part. I am not going to tell you anything about needing to write everyday, or holding yourself to some arbitrary word count. You are not Stephen King or JK Rowling, and you still have a day job or daytime responsibilities that aren't writing, be it child care, elder care, or any other sort of obligation that might prevent you from writing full time. You have responsibilities, and writing is currently a hobby you want to take further. You know your health, you know your levels of ability. If you &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to tell yourself to write every day, or hit some word count, that is up to you. But it is not &lt;em&gt;necessary&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set reasonable goals. When you first start, you will probably get a rush of words out, and feel that you can keep that pace going. Maybe you can, but do not get down on yourself if you can't. Do what is sustainable. Take the number of words or the time you spent at the get go and cut that in half. Try to make an effort to write when you are feeling good. Keep a notepad handy, or an app on your phone that you can sync, and jot down ideas as you have them. If you can't write words, let yourself count those notes as progress. Because they are progress. Eventually, as you hire an editor or enlist beta readers, you will need to set a deadline. Take a look at your calendar, see when you will have big obligations at work, or with your family, and try to be realistic about how much you will honestly get done during those weeks or months. The more you write, the better you will get at recognizing your pace and figuring out when you might be more productive than not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a common phrase around writing a novel, and it is "pants v plan." There are some people who sit down and start writing from the first chapter and keep going until they hit 'the end.' This is called 'pantsing.' You write by the seat of your pants, your plot twists and characters and arcs made up on the fly. This approach usually involves a ton of editing afterward, as changes you made along the way don't align with how you started it. The 'planning' approach usually invovles character profiles, a timeline, an outline, a page or two on major themes. It might involve going on google image search and trying to find photos of people who might look like what your characters look like. These character profiles can include detailed backstories, a list of their wants, their birthday, their eye color, their sun sign - any details that is pertinent or relevant to the story (and even some that are not) can be gathered in these documents. There might be setting write ups, descriptions about what a city looks like and what defines it and the people that live there. There might even be hand drawn maps. Time lines can have dates or a length of time to describe the chronology of several different characters. This detailed planning can take a lot of time and effort. People whotake this approach often do not have a lot of developmental editing to do afterward, but a huge chunk of time is spent before actually writing a single word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fall somewhere in the middle. I have a general outline, a few sentences on each character, and a rough write up of the major settings. But I tweak and change these on the fly and often end up with an ending that is different than what I thought I would have. Some authors have stories they pants and others they planned. You do not have to pick an approach and use that approach 100% correctly 100% of the time. You can do as much planning or pantsing as you think you need. It's ok to have the story change as you write it, it's ok to re-write major parts of your novel later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some great software programs out there to help both pantser and planners and those in-between. For years the go-to was &lt;a href="https://www.literatureandlatte.com/scrivener/overview"&gt;Scrivener&lt;/a&gt;. It has mobile apps now for Apple products, but not for Windows or Android yet. &lt;a href="http://storyist.com/"&gt;Storyist&lt;/a&gt; also as robust multi-device capabilities. Both of these have amazing tools to help you keep track of what you are doing. There are built in folders for character profiles and location write ups, and an amazing feature that lets you see your chapters at a glance. I highly recommend watching the tutorials for how to use these tools, as there are a ton of small features that can really let you focus on writing. Scrivener has a 30 day free trial - which is counted chronologically. If you use it for an hour, it counts it as an hour and you have 719 hours left in your trial. The next day, you use it for an hour, and now you have 718 hours left in your trial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You do not have to use a robust tool like Scrivener or Storyist, though. You can use Microsoft Word, Open Office Word, Google Docs, or Evernote. You can use Notepad or another text editor like Sublime or Atom. You can organize a folder on your desktop with a file for each chapter, and a file for each character profile. You can do the same in a Google Drive folder. I wrote "The Resignation Letter" and "A Lake of Feathers and Moonbeams" in Google Drive. Each draft had its own file. I am writing my next novel in Scrivener. I've used Scrivener for past NaNoWriMo's. I used an open source story editor, whose name I cannot recall right now, back in college for my senior thesis (ask me about international law, belligerent occupation, Hawai'i, and the difference between the Hawai'ian Indigenous Movement and the Hawaiian Sovereignty Movement, I promise not to bore you). It does not matter how you write. It might be worthwhile to try out several different tools or methods. Find one that you like, that you feel productive in, that you feel allows you to focus on the story, and use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some tools you definitely want to have on hand are a thesaurus, a dictionary, and a style guide. You can use online ones or physical ones. I find the thesaurus to be invaluable. Ever since I got a concussion in 2016, I have had aphasia. The thesaurus lets me find the words that used to come so easily. I have a dozen different style guides from my time as a creative writing major, and some really amazing writing books ("&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2Bjp1Ov"&gt;The Book of Other People&lt;/a&gt;" is one of my favorites). I have a ton of books on poetry ("&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2zy4sR9"&gt;Structure and Surprise&lt;/a&gt;" is one of my favorites), and a few on writing non-fiction, too. You do not have to own a dozen books on writing to be a good writer, but it certainly helps. Many libraries have these books, and some of them even have them as digital ebooks you can borrow. In truth, any book you read is going to help you be a better writer. If you are writing sci-fi, read other sci-fi books. Read the good ones and highlight phrases you liked and write down plot twists you enjoyed. Read the bad ones and highlight what you think makes it so bad. Look at the Goodreads nominations in the genre or type of writing you are doing and try to read three or four of them. These are books your library most certainly has! Try to read diversely. Yes, Stephen King is amazingly successful at horror, but he has a style that is constant through all his books. Try to find some smaller names in horror, from all over the world, with a whole slew of different experiences and writing styles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another resource, and I am not at all sorry for sending you down a rabbit hole, is &lt;a href="http://tvtropes.org"&gt;TVTropes&lt;/a&gt;. This is a huge wiki of commonly used tropes. You're going to use tropes. Tropes are short cuts. But you want to know how other people are using them or inverting them. Find a book that you like and find it's entry on TVTropes. Read about how it is or isn't playing into tropes. Some tropes are done to death, some have been inverted to hell and back. If your story contains one, look at the other media that uses it and figure out how &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; particular instance of trope was made unique. Some tropes are incredibly harmful. The "Bury Your Gays" trope, for instance, has been widely critiqued and criticized. If you don't know what it is, it is a trope wherein no gay or lesbian couple survives the book / tv show / movie in tact, as one of them will die tragically. You might want to re-examine if your story can be done without falling into this trope. You do not want to end up on a list of "500 stories where the lesbian dies and the one single story where she doesn't." Most tropes, in and of themselves, are not &lt;em&gt;bad writing&lt;/em&gt;. It is how you use them that can be critiqued. I dare you to find a IP on TvTropes that doesn't have at least 100 entries of tropes it uses. I'd say "I'll wait," but I have plans for what I want to do between now and the heat death of the universe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are tons of other writing resources out there, and I encourage you to read as many of them as you can. Next time, I will dig into editing, beta reading, and sensitivity reading and how and when you should and how to find people to do them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want this series, and other exclusive content, delivered right to your mailbox? I have a newsletter now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;form action="https://buttondown.email/api/emails/embed-subscribe/dax" method="post" target="popupwindow" onsubmit="window.open('https://buttondown.email/dax', 'popupwindow')" class="embeddable-buttondown-form"&gt;
  &lt;label for="bd-email"&gt;Enter your email&lt;/label&gt;
  &lt;input type="email" name="email" id="bd-email" /&gt;
  &lt;input type="hidden" value="1" name="embed" /&gt;
  &lt;input type="submit" value="Subscribe" /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href="https://buttondown.email" target="_blank"&gt;Powered by Buttondown.&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reflections on a first novel</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/reflections-on-a-first-novel/"/>
    <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog/reflections-on-a-first-novel/</id>
    <published>2017-11-18T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-19T12:21:49-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dax Murray</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Time works funny sometimes. It does not feel like all that long ago that I revealed the cover for  my first novel, &lt;em&gt;A Lake of Feathers and Moonbeams&lt;/em&gt;, and yet it has been months. Three long and exhausting months. &lt;em&gt;A Lake of Feathers and Moonbeams&lt;/em&gt; was ambitious, I set out on that journey late in the middle of the night in December 2016. It was cold, and snowing, and I couldn't sleep. I had been working on refining and revising &lt;em&gt;The Resignation Letter&lt;/em&gt; (at that time I was calling it &lt;em&gt;The Resignation Letter of the First Imperial Scientist&lt;/em&gt;) and I wanted something else to occupy my mind while I tried to fall asleep. I pulled out my phone and opened a new word document and began writing a first person account of running through the woods with crows and ravens following behind. I got to about 600 words in that untitled Google Doc before I felt like I was ready to go to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I forgot about that still untitled random bit of writing. I finished &lt;em&gt;The Resignation Letter&lt;/em&gt;, released it, and then felt a bit empty. I needed something else to write. I had not truly written anything in a few years. I had a bad person in my life, and this person not encouraging or supportive of my writing. They thought they &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; were true writers, writing was &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; thing. So I couldn't do it. Despite the fact that I minored in writing in college. I wasn't allowed to write, according to them. But in August 2016, I decided this person was not someone I wanted to be around anymore. And then my words began to flow again. I did not want that flow of words to dry up, to stop running, to stop nourishing me. In a round about way, &lt;em&gt;The Resignation Letter&lt;/em&gt; was my own way of saying "no more." With that out of the way, I wanted to write a happier story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I dug through my Google Drive and found this snippet. I began outlining, plotting, watching way too many youtube videos with ballerina's. I think this story lived in me longer than I was cognizant. In Sepetember, the Russian Grand Ballet came to DC. It was a night of a presidential debate. I should have been in the office waiting for servers to be crashed by the millions of donations pouring in. But I managed to get the night off so I could go see &lt;em&gt;Swan Lake&lt;/em&gt; at the Warner Theatre in DC. It was &lt;em&gt;gorgeous&lt;/em&gt;. We ended up with better seats than we paid for. My friends were using the restroom and an usher came to ask where we were sitting. I handed him my ticket and my friends and he took them all from me and handed me new ones. He gave us VIP tickets with servers right at the front of the balcony. He said all we needed to do was promise we would each get a drink or food. We were planning on that already!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story came in bursts. I wrote 5000 words one day and only 10 the next. I tried to not let myself feel bad about that. Halfway through I decided I wanted to tell the story from Alexis' PoV, too. So I went back and began very precisely outlining concurrent events. Then I decided I didn't want it to be in first person. So I went back and edited to all be in tight third person. Tatiana surprised me. I was not planning on her being in the story, I did not include her in any of my early character cards. But she felt right. The Mother of the Forest was not supposed to make an appearance until the end. But then I saw a tweet of Bee's that said lesbians and snakes were going to be a trope. And well, I had two snakes, and this was a really sapphic book, so, sure, let's have the Mother of the Forest take the form of a venomous snake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished the first draft of it sometime in July. It was 52,007 words. I had wanted it to be a novella, and I had told my editor it would be substantially shorter. But my first thought was &lt;em&gt;I did it&lt;/em&gt;! I wrote a book. It had been a dream of mine since childhood. I remember sitting at the family computer with my sister, brother, and cousin Angela as we tried to co-write an epic space adventure. I remember sitting on Muggle Pride's fanfic forum and posting chapters of a really dark "book five" before Order of the Phoenix was released. I remember when another fanfic writer, "TieFi", began posting her own works in a subforum. One day she posted a link to buy a physical copy of the book. I was a teen with a part time job, but I bought her book. It's still on my shelf! I remember re-writing &lt;em&gt;Lioness Rampant&lt;/em&gt; so that Alanna did not end up with George. All through it all I kept thinking I wanted to write my own stuff one day. And as I wrote that last word on that sloppy first draft, I knew I had done what I dreamed of doing for so long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I needed to destroy one fifth of it. Editing is &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt;. This edit resulted in those 600 words I had written 7 months earlier being deleted. Entirely. They had survived the transition to third person, the addition of characters, the re-writing of her back story (originally she  knew who she was). But now they were unnecessary to the story. These 600 words were what I had shared with several people when they asked for a sneak peak. And they are not even in the final draft. I somehow deleted 10,000 words. Even more were lost when I finished the revision after getting it back from the editor. More were added, though, too. Plot holes were fleshed out, detail was given to scenes, and a completely new chapter was added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now it is out in the world and the world can read it. It came out October 27th, and el oh el four days later NaNoWriMo started. I didn't have anything planned but I decided to try to get as much as I could during NaNoWriMo. Even though my word count isn't climbing, I am doing a ton of planning. I wrote both &lt;em&gt;A Lake of Feathers and Moonbeams&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Resignation Letter&lt;/em&gt; using Google Docs. Each story has its own folder, and in it I keep a doc on research, a doc on timelines, a doc on each character. Each version of the story, each draft, has it's own file, too. This time around I am using Scrivener, though. I first heard about it years ago and got the free trial and loved it. But I didn't have the means to purchase it until recently. So this will be the first one made exclusively in Scrivener.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can't tell you much about my next novel, but I can tell you it's set in a roughly 1910's Europe fantasy country, which means I am researching who had indoor plumbing and who didn't, who had electric lights and who didn't, and a lot more about a time period that had rapid technological advances. The main character is named Ana, after my grandmother. Ana lives with a ragtag bunch of queer kids living in a flat above a bakery. The current working title is &lt;em&gt;How To Lose A Throne&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am still undecided about if I am going to try to pitch this to agents or if I am going to self-publish it. Self publishing is &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt;. I loved that I did not have to worry about a cover being bad or wrong. I loved the complete control I had over the final product. But wow I suck at marketing. I am reading all these guides on having an author website and a mailing list and a facebook page and I am not sure if I can do all those things? I rarely update this blog, and half the time it's not about writing at all. It's about snakes or Ruby or frustrations with this or that programming language or framework. I don't want to have to seperate out my messy identity into different blogs, but that may happen. I my migrate the coding / tech posts to dax.codes at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ANYWAYS I DO NOT THINK I HAVE POSTED THIS BUT I HAVE MORE THAN JUST MELUSINA NOW.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/supermojave.jpg" alt="An all white ball python in a small container" style="max-width:46%; align: left" /&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/supermojave2.jpg" alt="An all white ball python in my hand flicking her tongue" style="max-width:46%; align: right" /&gt;
This is my NEW, so far unnamed, ball python. She hatched 8.25.2017, and her morph is "super mojave" or "blue eyed leucistic" - she is not albino, as albino ball pythons have yellow markings and red eyes. Mojave is what is called a "co-dominate" gene, so if a BP only has one copy of that gene, they look a little bit like normal ball pythons. They are still have markings, but the pattern is reduced, the browns are more like black, and it fades from spine to stomach. With two copies, you get an all white snake with a little bit of purple markings on the head. The mojave gene also can be paired with the "lesser" gene or the "russo" gene to get all white snakes which are also "blue eyed leucisits", but without the head markings. I specifically wanted a super mojave for the cute purple head markings. She's getting settled in still, so I don't have a ton of picutres of her yet. She ate for me for the first time on Friday. I can't decide on what her name should be, I've got some ideas but, still haven't picked one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/calcifer.jpg" alt="A Brazilian Rainbow Boa in my hand" style="max-width:50%;" /&gt; 
This is my Brazilian Rainbow Boa, Calcifer! I got him back in April but I don't recall if I ever posted a picture of him here. He's super great, he isn't a morph, just a regular normal coloration and pattern. I'll get around someday to making an indepth care guide for Brazilian Rainbow Boa's like I did for Ball Pythons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've got a cool side project I am working on, I bought snakes.cool and am trying to make a nice website for tons of care guides and product recommendations for keeping various types of non-venomous snakes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cover Reveal for A Lake of Feathers and Moonbeams</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/cover-reveal-and-preorder/"/>
    <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog/cover-reveal-and-preorder/</id>
    <published>2017-08-02T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-08-03T21:50:32-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dax Murray</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's here! Louisa of &lt;a href="https://juneberrydesign.myportfolio.com/"&gt;Juneberry Designs&lt;/a&gt; has finished the cover of &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2v1opfg"&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Lake of Feathers and Moonbeams&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and it looks &lt;em&gt;fantastic&lt;/em&gt;. I could not be happier! The novella itself has been written, and it clocked in at 52,009 words. About 7,000 more words than I wanted it to be. I did a lot of editing to get it back down to 45,117 words. Some of the cuts were hard to make but ultimately I knew the scenes I cut were slowing down the pacing. They were cute scenes! Maybe I will release them uneditted here or in a newletter one day (I would have to make a newsletter) but for now they are sitting in a folder collecting dust. I sent the editted novel to Jen of &lt;a href="http://www.clearingblocksediting.com/"&gt;Clearing Blocks Editing&lt;/a&gt; to do some more edits! If you have not yet noticed from the link at the top, it is available for pre-order! It should be hitting your kindles at the end of October.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/ALoFaMCover-01.jpg" alt="Three people stand on the edge of a lake while an owl menaces them from above" style="max-width:100%;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Ultimate Ball Python Care Guide</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/Ultimate-Ball-Python-Care-Guide/"/>
    <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog/Ultimate-Ball-Python-Care-Guide/</id>
    <published>2017-08-01T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-08-03T21:51:39-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dax Murray</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've learned a ton since I first got Melusina in February, and I've been working on a more comprehensive guide based on my experience and my research. I am working on making a dedicated site for my snake ramblings, but for now I am gonna post a ton of good information here while still trying to get Jekyll to play nice with PureCSS's grid system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ball pythons are a very shy snake, and while they are beautiful and docile, even the tiniest bit of stress can send them down the road of a hunger strike. They will 'go off feed' for months at a time (it has happened to me!) and you can triple check and quadrupal check your husbandry and still be baffled as to why your snake isn't eating. To a beginner, this can be escpecially firghtening. Here I have outlined some of the basics of keeping  ball python along with product recommendations. Most of these will be from Amazon, but some of them will be from reptile specific companies. I recommend that you purchase everything you will need at least two weeks before you bring the actual snake home with you, so that you can get everything set up and make adjustments if you have to. When I got my boa, I had his home set up a week before hand and that allowed me to observe humidity, temps, and make small adjustments before he arrived!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Humidity&lt;/em&gt;
A ball python needs at the minimum 60% humidity. This is incredibly difficult to achieve in a glass tank with a screen top. A tub or PVC enclosure makes this super easy as there is less airflow. Humidity should be measured on the ground with a digital hygrometer. The stick on humidity gauges that pet stores hawk are often inaccurate and can cause &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/snakes/comments/6f1zjy/snake_injured_by_humidifier_gauge/"&gt;serious injury&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/snakes/comments/55qtgm/update_2_tiamat_the_snake_stuck_to_adhesive_has/"&gt;even death&lt;/a&gt; if they come unstuck from the wall and stick to your snake. I use &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2fcsrMB"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; two in one hygrometer / thermometer. I use a dab of hot glue to affix the probe to the center of the warm side of the enclosure, and keep the unit itself on the cool side. This way the "outdoor" temp shows my warm side, and the "indoor temp" shows the cool side/ambient temperature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Temperature&lt;/em&gt;
Ball pythons need a thermo-gradiant w one "warm" end  between 88F and 90F and a "cool" end of 78Fish - the ambient temperature should never be below 75F, &amp;amp; should be around high 70's. In a tub or a PVC enclosure, you will want an under tank heater - heat tap, heat mats, heat pads. I recommend the flexwatt that you can get with the Animal Plastics enclosure or the &lt;a href="http://www.reptilebasics.com/ultratherm-heat-pads"&gt;ultratherm from Reptile Basics&lt;/a&gt;. If you have trouble keeping the ambient up in the PVC enclosure, you may want to get a &lt;a href="http://www.reptilebasics.com/rbi-radiant-heat-panels"&gt;radiant heat panel&lt;/a&gt;, which installs to the ceiling of the enclosure. For a glass tank, you will probably need a ceramic heat emitter installed over the cage to keep ambient temperatures appropriate. CHE sucks out humidity, so you will need to be extra on top of that. CHE gives off no visible light. Red lights are often given out like candy at PetCo/Smart places as good ways to provide heat at night. They are not. Ball pythons can see red light, and it messes up their day/night cycle.  You will also want an &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2vnG41U"&gt;IR thermometer gun&lt;/a&gt;. This is good for spot checking temperatures without moving around probes &amp;amp; also checking the temps of the prey items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thermostats&lt;/em&gt;
Any &amp;amp; all heat sources you have for your ball python need to be controlled by a thermostat. Failure to appropriately control your heat source can lead to it quickly becoming 120F and &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/snakes/comments/6ihxu8/need_help_with_my_ball_python_belly_is_hurt_and/"&gt;injuring your snake&lt;/a&gt;. I highly recommend &lt;a href="http://www.spyderrobotics.com/index.php?main_page=product_info&amp;amp;cPath=1&amp;amp;products_id=25"&gt;Spyder Robotics Herpstats&lt;/a&gt;. You can get larger ones w more probes so that you can control all your heat sources w one unit. They have a ton of good safety features.. The cheaper ones are around $100ish. If that is too much for you, there are a lot of people who use the &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2wcbMg5"&gt;Jumpstart&lt;/a&gt; thermostats, but they have less safety features &amp;amp; can wear out quickly. They also make a loud clicking sound periodically. I cannot stress this enough, this is not a place to cut corners. You need a thermostat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PVC Enclosure I have has cut outs on the bottom of the enclosure to put thermostat probes. I have the probe in that slot, and the under tank heater taped with aluminum tape to the outside bottom. The heat goes through the plastic and heats the floor of the enclosure. I have the thermostat set to 98F, and that puts the floor temperature of the enclosure at 90F. Even though I have the thermostat, I also always check the thermometer I have affixed to the inside floor to make sure the thermostat is working. For Radient Heat Panels, you wil want to dangle the probe next to the RHP. The RHP will be screwed to the ceiling, and you then dril a hole to dangle the probe through or drill a hole on the side to slide it in and then affix it to the ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enclosure&lt;/em&gt;
Glass tanks with screen lids are very bad for ball pythons. Glass tanks are bad at keeping heat in, and the screen lid is bad at keeping humidity in. For a cheap but effective route, you could look at getting a tub set up (using a rubber maid/sterilite /iris tub &amp;amp; soldering or drilling holes into the sides - here is a&lt;a href="https://ball-pythons.net/forums/showthread.php?113879-My-Plastic-Tub-Setup-for-my-Ball-Python"&gt; good tutorial of setting that up&lt;/a&gt; ). I highly recommend the &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2fcVgsk"&gt;Iris Weathertight&lt;/a&gt;, it has plenty of clips on the edge for security. If you choose another type, without these locking clamps, you should also look at luggage straps for security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another option is a PVC enclosure. I have an &lt;a href="http://www.apcages.com/home/"&gt;Animal Plastics&lt;/a&gt; T8 for my ball python. It has sliding glass doors, I installed LED's myself, and I got it with the flexwatt under tank heater. It came unassembled, but with clear directions, I was able to build it and install my LED lighting in a single evening.  Another reputable maker of PVC cages is &lt;a href="http://www.boaphileplastics.com/"&gt;Boaphile&lt;/a&gt;, I have not had direct experience with them, but their cages come pre-assembled, and you can ask for the lighting and heating to already be set up. For my Animal Plastics cage, it did take about five weeks for it to show up. If you want to go this route, plan way ahead. The tub route is cheaper, but takes more DIY skills. The PVC cage route is more expensive, but very aesthetically pleasing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is absolutely no way around having a glass tank, you can cover three sides of it in foam board (ball pythons hate being exposed) to give them more security, and to help keep some heat in. You can also cover about 3/4ths of the screen lid in saran wrap to help keep humidity in. Using a substrate like coconut husk can also help with humidity. You may still end up having to mist the tank a few times a day, and you may have to keep the temperature of the room the tank is in higher to help out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of what type of enclosure you get, it should be kept in a room with minimal sound and activity. Keeping it in a busy living room will result in a stressed ball python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hides&lt;/em&gt;
You want at least two similar, enclosed hides. &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Zoo-Med-Habba-Extra-Large/dp/B0010ONMV4/"&gt;Half logs&lt;/a&gt; are &lt;em&gt;NOT&lt;/em&gt; suitable, they are too open &amp;amp; they stress out the BP, as they can't watch both ends at once for a predator. Some of the best hides are &lt;a href="http://www.reptilebasics.com/hide-boxes"&gt;these ones from Reptile Basics&lt;/a&gt;. They are enclosed on all sides with just a small entrance. They are dishwasher safe &amp;amp; also very cheap. If you want a more naturalistic looking hide, &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2v43Ptj"&gt;these&lt;/a&gt; are suitable as they are enclosed on all sides and have only one entrance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want them to be similar if not identical, so that the snake does not have to choose between feeling safe &amp;amp; thermoregulating. You will want one on each side of the temperature gradient. Feel free to add more that are different for diversity in the enclosure. I also have some &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2fckrLk"&gt;fake vines&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2vnM6zy"&gt;leaves&lt;/a&gt; in mine so that she feels more invisible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Water dish&lt;/em&gt;
You will want a water bowl that is large enough for the ball python to soak in. This should be changed daily, as they like to poop &amp;amp; pee in their water. You'll want something sturdy as they like to tip them over. I got some &lt;a href="http://www.reptilebasics.com/water-bowls"&gt;crock dishes from Reptile Basics&lt;/a&gt;. You don't need any water treatment for the snakes water unless you treat water for yourself. If you tap is safe for human consumption, it's safe for your snake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Feeding&lt;/em&gt;
Ball pythons eat every 5 - 7 days as hatchlings and yearlings, as adults they can go longer. Ball pythons are NOTORIOUSLY picky eaters. The ideal for a ball python is a proper sized rat fed either pre-killed or frozen/thawed. I feed frozen/thawed rats from &lt;a href="http://www.perfectprey.com/frozen-rats/"&gt;Perfect Prey&lt;/a&gt;. Just a heads up - they ship with fiber glass insulation &amp;amp; dry ice. I try to open the packages outside so my cats don't get into it. They come in freezer bags and I just store them in my regular freezer. If even one thing is wrong in your husbandry, your ball python will likely not eat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How Much To Feed&lt;/em&gt;
The feeding amount depends on the weight of the ball python. You will want a &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2v4omOf"&gt;digital kitchen scale&lt;/a&gt;. While under 750g, you want to feed about 10%-15% of their body weight about every 7 days. Once they are in their second year you want to feed  7%-10% of their body weight, after they are in their third year, you want to feed about 5% every 7 to 14 days. I document all feeding days and the weight of the prey in my google calender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should be weighing your snake at least once a month to track how much you should be feeding. You should not disturb or move or handle your snake for at least 48 hours after feeding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frozen / Thawed&lt;/em&gt;
I get the rat out the night before the day I want to feed. I put it in the fridge. About two hours before I feed, I get it out of the fridge and put it on the counter to get it to room temp. And then I soak it in a zip lock bag in warmish water (I use a temp gun to get water around 110F) for about 20 minutes, and use a temp gun to make sure the rat is around 100F, and then I run the head under running hot water until its 110F. The head of the prey should be warmer so the snake has a target. I then use tongs to move it around in the enclosure to mimic it being alive. She (usually) strikes pretty quickly. If she doesn't, I leave it in overnight, and throw it out in the morning if she doesn't eat it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I prefer frozen thawed cause I can buy cheaply in bulk. It's also safer. As ball pythons get bigger, they require larger prey - and rats have sharp teeth and sharp claws and can seriously injure your snake. Mice are not as nutriucious as rats, and as your ball python gets older, mice will be too small to be a full meal, meaning you will have to feed multiple prey items. Feeding multiple prey items is stressful on the snake and usually after they swallow one, they are reluctant to try another. The sooner you switch to rats, the easier your life will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Myths of Cage Aggression&lt;/em&gt;
You do not need a separate cage for feeding it. This is a myth. The best way to reduce stress at feeding time is to feed in their regular enclosure. This minimizes the risk of regurgitation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Substrate&lt;/em&gt;
Stay away from aromatic woods - such as pine. A lot of people like to use coconut husk, unprinted newspaper, or paper towels. Newspaper and paper towels are cheap and it is easy to clean up messes. They do not help raise humidity, though. &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2v1uckY"&gt;Coconut husk&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2fd4DIs"&gt;ReptiHhip&lt;/a&gt; are great for a naturalistic look and can help keep or raise humidity. They require soaking in water before hand, and then either allowing to dry or baking. I will soak them in water over night, and then let them air dry for a bit before throwing them in the stove for about an hour at 250F. After I get them out, I let them cool down and then add to the enclosure. You can remove them both, rinse and bake them multiple times. These should last a year before you need to buy new. I scoop out the solid wastes when I see them, and then every few months rinse and bake. There might be small wood mites in these, but the baking process or boiling it before hand should kill them. There should not be snake mites in these. Either way, boiling or baking will kill them. If you have a chip type substrate and are worry about ingestion of substrate while feeding, put a plate down before hand. Aspen can mold super easily so not really recommended unless you want to be changing out your substrate often, which might stress out your ball python.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Announcing: A Lake of Feathers and Moonbeams</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/Announcing-A-Lake-of-Feathers-and-Moonbeams/"/>
    <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog/Announcing-A-Lake-of-Feathers-and-Moonbeams/</id>
    <published>2017-05-15T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-08-03T19:51:15-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dax Murray</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I wanted to formally announce my forthcoming novella, due to be released this fall. It is an #ownvoices queer re-telling of &lt;em&gt;Swan Lake,&lt;/em&gt; and I am really excited to share it with you when it comes out. I am going to be self-publishing this novella, just as &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01MS9NU7F"&gt;The Resignation Letter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; was self-published. &lt;a href="https://juneberrydesign.myportfolio.com/"&gt;Louisa&lt;/a&gt; will again be doing the cover for me, and I've asked Jen of &lt;a href="http://www.clearingblocksediting.com/"&gt;Clearing Blocks Editing&lt;/a&gt; to help me out with making sure everything is PERFECT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've been putting together and &lt;a href="https://www.pinterest.com/daxaeterna/a-lake-of-feathers-and-moonlight/"&gt;pinterest board&lt;/a&gt; for it, and I hope you'll check that out. I've also definitely got a playlist for when I am writing it, here are the &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/music/playlist/AMaBXynmGGrclnddDFOND_5TPoYX5hx48SwXvW60gMuRVsEokrWeAkWfnFkzGrJ11XMDbIPk2LbhD65yEFC23oZ4hJrxlkuZ8Q%3D%3D"&gt;top songs&lt;/a&gt; on it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Girl in a Coma - As the World Falls Down&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blackmore's Night - Where Are We Going From Here&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fleetwood Mac - Rhiannon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stevie Nicks - Beauty and the Beast&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blackmore's Night - Gilded Cage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kate Voegele - Devil In Me (Live Demo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Distant Worlds/Nobou Uematsu - Distant Worlds with Susan Calloway&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blood Ceremony - Goodbye Gemini&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Florence and the Machine - Howl&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Florence and the Machine - Cosmic Love&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the potential blurb:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;At the center of the forest there is a lake. On a cool night, moonbeams kissed the waters and Katya was born. Since then she has kept company with the crows and the eccentric sorcerer, Ivan, who has made his home there. She soars through the night as a swan alongside her crow sisters, and does errands for Ivan during the day. She never believed that her life would every be spent any differently, being content with her minor magics and charms and safe beside Ivan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When a group of soldiers escorting the princess Yi Zhen from neighboring kingdom of Shān come through her woods, she is shocked to find Ivan taking the princess as his prisoner. He asks Katya to disguise herself as another captive to glean information from the princess. Thus she spends her days feigning captivity alongside a princess whom she is slowly falling for.  A princess who is betrothed to the Princen Alexis of Lebedia, who is surely searching for her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Katya finds herself entwined in a complex web of politics, grudges, betrayal and heartache spanning centuries. At the heart of this web she must find out who she is, and what she stands for, and what she is willing to sacrifice to stay true to herself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A nuanced re-telling of "Swan Lake" from the perspective of the black swan, this story explores love and loyalty, how both are won, earned, destroyed, or betrayed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to request an Advanced Reader Copy, please let me know by reaching out to me on &lt;a href="https://www.twitter.com/daxaeterna"&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;. I am hoping to have some ARC's out in September.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
