<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Dax Murray</title>
  <subtitle>Books. Coding. Feminism. (Cats.)</subtitle>
  <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog</id>
  <link href="http://daxmurray.com/blog"/>
  <link href="http://daxmurray.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-05-12T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Dax Murray</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Review: The Seafarer's Kiss by Julia Ember</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/review-the-seafarers-kiss/"/>
    <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog/review-the-seafarers-kiss/</id>
    <published>2017-05-12T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-05-13T13:14:47-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dax Murray</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;content note: discussion of rape, trans misogyny, violence against trans people&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was incredibly excited when I heard about "The Seafarer's Kiss" by Julia Embers - it seemed like everything I love. It was a fairy tale retelling. It was told from the point of view of the traditional villain in that tale, and it was going to be queer and it was going to have a character that uses they/them pronouns. In case you missed it, I am queer and non-binary, and my pronouns are fey/fem/feir/feirs/femself, just like they/them/their but with an 'f' - so I was so ready for a book with someone who seemed like me, multiple someones, perhaps!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was excited because the author is bi, like me. The author is poly, like me. And from reviews of the authors other work, "Unicorn Tracks", it seemed as hough the author really cared about getting representation &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt;. I was very sorely disappointed and hurt by this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started out very, very good. We meet Ersel, a mermaid who lives in an ice glacier somewhere near Norway, and who is very upset by the upcoming Grading. In the world Ersel lives in, mermaids are judged based on how fertile they are. At 19 years old they take part in a ritual to determine their fertility, and are then coerced into choose a mate. Once mated, many of these young women are confined to the darkness and spend the rest of their lives laying eggs. It's pretty patriarchal, and the reader immediately identifies with Ersels desire for a different future. Ersel, like many YA lady protagonists, declares herself not like the other girls a ton during this exposition on her plight. Many other mermaids of Ersel's age are shown taking care of themselves in an effort to increase their fertility, including Vigdis, who is sometimes cruel to Ersel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of Ersel's "not like the other girls" characteristics is that she explores shipwrecks, and steals treasures from them and hides them in her cave in their ice home. Her best friend, Havamal, used to go with her, but since he joined the King's Guard, he has been busy. He also believes he is now grown up, and doesn't need the childhood fantasy they used to share of running away. He chides Ersel for her continued desire to escape their patriarchal king and her ongoing searches of the water tombs of humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the grading happens, it turns out Ersel is incredibly fertile, probably the most fertile mermaid their clan has seen. They need to reproduce, as their clan is dying out. It also turns out that she was born in the season of Loki, something she hadn't really considered or known before. In a cruel twist of irony, Vigdis is not fertile, despite all her attempts. Vigdis is crushed, forelorn, and despondent by this news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything changes when Ersel happens upon a stranded sheild maiden, Ragna, trapped on the ice. Ersel decides to help this human, and brings her food, wood of sunken ships, and helps keep her warm so that Ragna can fix the lifeboat she escaped the sinking ship on and sail back home. Ragna was stolen from her villaige as a gift for someone else, and she intends to find this someone else and extract revenge. Ersel identifies with Ragna's desire for freedom, and the two share a very cute moment. The cuteness doesn't last as Ersel is caught by Havamal, who threatens to report her to the king. He is a huge asshole, telling her he will spare Ragna's life if Ersel agrees to be his mate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeling trapped and hopeless, she is confronted by Loki. Loki offers her a wish if she obtains a mermaids voice for them. Ember's version of Loki is genderfluid, or non-binary, and uses they them pronouns. Anyone familiar with Norse mythology would know that Loki is the trickster god. Ember stays true to this, and Loki is not to be trusted. Ersel makes a deal anyways. Ersel finds Vigdis, and tells her that if she gives up her voice, she can have the fertility she wants. Vigdis agrees, and asks for a mate, too. Ersel takes the voice back to Loki, and asks for legs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loki grants her legs, but they are not the legs of a human that Ersel had imagined, but instead the legs of an octopus. And Vigdis? A mate in the form of a monster comes for her, and she does indeed become pregnant, and later dies from the pregnancy. Ersel is expelled from her clan, and forced to live elsewhere, making her own way and getting her own fod.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Loki visits her again, she strikes another deal, this time trying to outsmart the trickster god. At this point, I was incredibly upset. The only character who seemed to not be a binary cis person was Loki. Loki had been cruel, deceiptful, and their actions had resulted in what I would consider to be rape. The monster that had come for Vigdis had originally come in the form of a handsome merman, and she consented to that intercourse. But then the creature had changed, and she was distraught to find herself deceived. The resulting pregnancy was not a normal occurance for merfolk, the pregnancy was like that of a mammal, and her body was not equipped for it. She and the fetus she carried died during delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loki laughed at this, and Loki laughed at this while using Vigdis's voice. Loki's own voice had been sealed by Thor, and they needed to steal other voices to be able to communicate. I was very sickened by what Loki was doing, and I believe that was the point. The readers are supposed to be upset, Loki is a villain, and villains need to be evil. What Loki did was beyond a moral event horizon for most people on this Earth. This would have been good story telling, this would have been good villain writing if Loki wasn't a trans non-binary person. If Loki wasn't the only trans person, the only non-binary person, in the novel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ersel goes on to make another deal with Loki, and we learn that the creature that they had set upon Vigdis had once been a human, and Loki had transformed them into a monster and took away their free will. There is a hard to read conversation where this creature explains that during this time, he becomes a passive observer of what Loki is using their body for, but sometimes he enjoys it. This is a pretty nuanced character, where we see how badly he has been abused, and how some part of him is in conflict over how he feels when this happens. His body had been used by Loki to rape Vigdis, and he was conflicted about if the monstrosity was inside him all along, or if that was something that Loki had put inside of him. I both hated and pitied him, and Ersel granted him freedom in death. I was pretty impressed with how well that scene was handled, and I had hopes that my discomfort with how Loki was being handled would end up being righted, and Ember would grant nuance to Loki.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was wrong. Loki tries very hard for much the rest of the novel to out-trick Ersel, going so far as to say they invented lying, they invented deception. At about 80%, Ersel finishes her last bargain with Loki, having done some pretty amoral things to get there. With the help of her mother, she is able to get her mermaid form back, and she is able to transform herself into a human, or take on her octopus-like form, too. Loki gives her the information she needs to take down the patriarchal tyrant and then departs. We don't see them again. The remaining 20% of the book is a pretty great plot to overthrow the patriarchy, which I am always down for, but I couldn't enjoy it. I was too hurt by how Loki had been handled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know the author is bi, and I want to believe her intentions were good, that she was trying to add diversity to her book. I don't know if she had sensetivity readers for Loki, and if she did, I don't know what they said. They might have liked the portrayal for all I know. But I was hurt. Trans people are currently cast in our society as liars, deceivers, con artist who lie about their gender in order to trick people. We are cast as villains trying to trick our way into spaces that aren't ours, like bathrooms. "Trans panic", in which a cis person, usually a man, finds out that the woman he is dating is trans and murders her, is a defense that has been held up in a court of law. You can claim "trans panic" and not get sentenced to prison for murder. And this defense works because it relies on the falsity that trans people are tricksters, liars, masters of deception and that this deception is so heinous that a citizen can act as judge, jury and executioner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book has one trans character, and that character is literally the inventor of lying. The god of deception. The master of deceit. Can you see how this is harmful? Can you see how this perpetuates false, negetive stereoptypes about trans people? How this reinforces the narrative that society has crafted about us?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, Loki is genderqueer, non binary, genderfluid. We are further marginalized for this refusal to be inside the gender binary. We are doing it for attention, we are making it up, we are not "right" - we get mocked with phrases like "I identify as an attack helicopter," we can't even change our gender markers in most places. To have the only non-binary character in your book be a liar is not helping to dispell any of these sentiments about us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is so little representation of genderqueer, non-binary people in books, especially in YA. I was trying to think of positive examples of this done right after someone on twitter asked me for recommendations. I've been throught this before, I am bi, and I spent so much time trying to track down books with a bi protagonist. Or any bi people at all. I had so few examples when I was growing up. I am so glad to see there is now a great selection of YA books with bi protagonists. But options for enby's are few and far between.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With so little representation, I think it was incredibly harmful. I believe a second enby character in this book, one who was positive and good and whom the reader knew had a moral compass, would have gone a long way towards allowing Loki to be complicated, messy, villainous, without unintentionally tying their evilness to their genderqueerness. Maybe in the future every book will have enbies in them, and we can have full on evil enbies because being enby is just accepted and of course enbies aren't a monolith. But without the good enbies saving the world in YA to counterbalance the bad enbies wrecking shit in YA, I can't find a way to see anything in Loki but a harmful propagation of stereotypes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I want to be perfectly clear, I am not hurt by Loki being the villain. I am hurt by the way that villainy is portrayed. If Loki was &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a god of lies and deception and trickery, I think this would have been a very different review. I am hurt by the fact that we have scarcely any positive representation at all and that this was sold as positive representation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, this book had some great cis bi, lesbian, queer woman rep. It was really cute, and really fun. But no amount of really good, really positive cis queer rep can make a really bad portrayal of a trans enby justified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few other things I wanted to point out that irked me a bit about this, and makes me leery to rec it to others. First, the main couple phsyically assault each other, and it felt really unnecessary. It felt out of place. The dialogue was conveying the conflict in view points between the two, there was no reason that I could see for their conflict to escalate to physical violence. The fact that neither apologizes for hitting the other, and that a very short amount of time later, they were back to being incredibly cute, felt like the violence was normative and ok. It wasn't.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, I mentioned the not like other girls thread earlier. It does end up resolving with "all the other girls felt just as trapped as you did," but it definitely could have been more explored as to how Ersel felt when realizing that. The start of the book was so heavy on this, and it felt like an afterthought at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, at the end, when they are confront one of the villains, Ersel comments that she used to think this particular villain was handsome, but now she can see his pockmarked face and "maybe the cruelty inside him was beginning to show on the outside." I really hate this line. Can we not equate beauty with goodness? This seems to undo all the work that was done for the previous 90% of the novel in showing that Ersel's kraken form was not a reflection of what was inside.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Snake Love</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/snake-love/"/>
    <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog/snake-love/</id>
    <published>2017-02-13T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-14T20:39:50-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dax Murray</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/me_an_melusina.jpg" alt="Me holding my snake in front of my face" style="max-width: 50%; float: right;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I adopted a snake recently! Her name is Melusina, she was hatched in July 2016 and she is a yellow belly ball python. "Yellow belly" is her "morph" - what snake breeders use to describe patterns / markings / genetics. There's a whole system of dominate / co-dominate / recessive traits breeding that goes on to make some really awesome looking snakes. "Ball python" is the type of snake she is. Ball pythons are medium sized snakes that are non-venomous. They are constrictors, which means they kill their prey by squeezing them. They are also sometimes called "royal pythons" because royalty in sub-Saharan nations would sometimes wear them as jewelry. The monikor "ball python" comes from the fact that balling up is their response to pretty much anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/melusina_flames.JPG" alt="a ball python's backside as wrapped around a human wrist" style="max-width: 50%; float: left;" /&gt;
Yellow bellies have "flames" coming up from their bellies. So the pattern would normally be solid black, but instead, inside of the black, there are some orange-ish flames. You can see my snakes "flames" pretty well in the light. Yellow bellies also have an orange smudgey triangle on their heads. It's a morph that was first "discovered" in 1999, and it's a dominante gene. If you breed two yellow bellies together, you will probably get a super yellow belly, or what is known sometimes as an ivory, which is a snake that is mostly all off- white with a very faint yellow pattern. Melusina's dad was an ivory ball python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/world_of_pets.jpg" alt="farm animals at a pet expo, including goats and miniature horse" style="max-width: 50%; float: right;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've wanted a pet snake for awhile now, and have had my heart set on ball pythons since college, when one of my sorority sisters had a snake she kept in her dorm room and sometimes brought out for various campus events. A few weeks ago I was at the Maryland World of Pets Expo with my friend &lt;a href="http://uncorkedunwrapped.com"&gt;Liz&lt;/a&gt; and we had a ton of fun meeting goats, alpacas, very large rabbits, very small horses, ducks, dogs who did tricks, cats who slept, and lots and lots of very good dogs that Brent would approve of. We eventually found our way to the reptile dealers, where some woman was very non-chalantly holding a scorpion. Down a little ways from her was a ton of snakes, and I asked if I could hold one. I ended up holding a banana ball python, and really wanted to take her home with me. The dealer said he could set up a kit for me and I could take the snake home with me today! However, the partner that I live with is kinda really scared of snakes. I texted anyways asking if it was ok, very jokingly. I didn't get a response until after we were pulling out of the expo and heading back home. But the response was "Sure."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I spent the next few days talking it over, doing some research, and triple checking that my partner was actually fine with me getting a python. I called up some Petco's and Petsmarts to ask if they carried ball pythons, not because I wanted to purchase one from a chain retailer, but because I wanted to know if they might have the correct supplies for me. I got on craigslist and tried to find some snakes for adoption on there, but wasn't really finding any ball pythons. I googled for reptile stores in DC, and found one in Baltimore. Finally I did the desperate thing and got on reddit, which is how I found &lt;a href="http://morphmarket.com"&gt;MorphMarket&lt;/a&gt;, which is a pretty new site, but it has inventory of hundreds of reptile breeders and reptile specialty stores, you can look by reptile type, and on the ball python end you could look on genetics, making it easy to find an Ivory (or "super yellow belly") or Banana or Albino or really any other fancy patterns. I used their map functionality to find a breeder (&lt;a href="https://www.osmunreptiles.com/"&gt;Osmun Reptiles&lt;/a&gt;) about twenty minutes from my place, and used MorphMarket to send an inquire about a hatchling he had. He responsed very promptly, and gave me a ton of good info about her. I let him know I was pretty local and while he could ship the snake, I wanted to pick her up in person and not risk it with it being winter. Breeders can often overnight live reptiles by putting heating packs in the box, but if there is a problem and it gets delayed, or it gets left on your porch and you don't get home for several hours, it can turn disasterous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With payment made and pick up arranged for the upcoming weekend, I started shopping for supplies for her. I waded through tons of care sheets from pet stores and pet supply manufacturers like Zoo Med and Zilla. I watched YouTube Videos from LLL Reptiles and other places like them on how to set up a snake habitate. They all had glass acquariums with screen tops, and said you needed a heating lamp and an under tank heater, like a heating pad. They said you could get a cheap substrate like aspen shavings, and that the heater went on one side (which would be your snakes "hot" side) and the other side should not have a heater (and be your snakes "cool" side). Most of them said you should have a "hide" on each side, or a small dark enclosure in which your snake could hide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went back to reddit, ready to ask questions that the videos did not answer. I went back /after/ I'd purchased a lot of stuff. I started reading, and reading, and reading, not quiet wanting to ever actually need to post on reddit, and therefore combing through the archives trying to find what I needed. The first thing I found was a rather tragic post of someone's snake removing the stick on thermometer in the tank and getting stuck to it. This did not end well for the snake, and I was really sad. I then checked the thermometer I'd purchased. Oops. Same one. I learned that if there is an adhesive surface in the tank, the snake will find a way to get to it, so don't stick anything to the tank walls with tape, sticky tack, command strips, etc. If you need to attach something to the tanks inner walls, use hot glue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next thing I learned is that tanks are actually pretty bad for snakes! They don't hold heat, and with the screen top, it makes keeping the necessary heat in a constant battle. With a screen top, humditiy also becomes difficult to maintain. A ball pythons cool side should always be above 75 F, and the warm side should not ever be above 95 F, preferrably no higher than 90 F. The humidity should always be above 50%, and during shed, it should be around 70%. I also had purchased aspen bedding, which sucks up a lot of moisture, and misting your tank to try to get the humidity up could easily cause a mold outbreak in the aspen substrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found links to places like &lt;a href="http://www.apcages.com/home/"&gt;Animal Plastics&lt;/a&gt;  and &lt;a href="http://pvccages.com/"&gt;PVC Cages&lt;/a&gt;. I know the webpages is incredibly sketchy looking, but multiple people on reddit vouched for it, and several of them I saw in multiple threads explaining how to treat snake emergencies, so I started to trust them even though they were often not the most pleasant people, since they obviously just wanted snakes to live a happy life. These enclsures were advocated as a pretty optimal place to keep a pet snake. You can buy the enclosure, the heating sources, and lighting sources all at once. They apparently last decades, and require very little by way of cleaning and upkeep. I'd already sunk a ton of money into my supplies, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already knew that baby ball pythons can get really scared of large spaces, so while mine is just a hatchling, she would need a smaller space. So I decided to try to make the best of what I had, and save up for a larger enclosure for her by way of either PVC Cages or Animal Plastics. First, I got two &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2kQT4XB"&gt;heating pads&lt;/a&gt;. These are adhesive, and meant to be stuck to the outside bottom of your tank, not the inside. The thing they don't tell you is that they can't really be bent, and bending them breaks them. So once it's on the tank, it's not coming off without breaking. However, as I learned on reddit, you can use the adhesive to stick it on tin foil, and then tape it onto the bottom outside of the tank with a heat resistant tape. I put one at each end of my tank, since it's glass and not great at heat. I then plugged them both into a &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2kHYwcU"&gt;thermostat&lt;/a&gt;. On the one side I set the temperature to 90F, and on the other, 78F. These aren't the most expensive thermostats, and there are some that are $600 USD and made specifically for reptile enclosures. This way the temperature in the enclsure would always be above 75F. The thermostates have probes to check the temperature, they come with suction cups. Don't be tempted to put the probes inside the enclosure. Instead put them in between the heating pad and the glass, the snake will find a way to move them, and if the snake sits on it in the enclsure, you might end up with a wrong temperature reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then got a foam poster board, and cut it up and taped it to the back and the sides of the glass tank. This achieves two things. First, it makes the snake feel more secure. Second, it acts as insulation for the glass, helping to keep the heat in. In addition, I got saran wrap and covered abut two-thirds of the screen top. I was now getting the right temperature readings, so I didn't need to rely on a heat lamp, and could use LED lights to illuminate the enclosure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ordered bricks of &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2leYqNx"&gt;coconut fiber&lt;/a&gt; substrate, which I then soaked in water and put in. I didn't soak it in too much water, just enough to get it to not be so compact. This helped keep the humidity up, and didn't have such a high risk of mold that the aspen bedding did. YOu don't need much substrate, you could actually get away with using papertowels as substrate if you wanted. I like the look of the coconut husks and it's helpful during shed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made the mistake of ordering too small a water bowel, none of the care sheets or videos from Big Brands explained that the snake should be able to fully fit into the water bowel in some manner. So I made sure to go to a pet store and find an appropriate sized one instead of relying on internet measurements to try to figure out if she could fit in it. Snakes will sometimes soak themselves in their water bowels to help with shedding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the probes used for the thermostates, I have two other &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2lf6HRy"&gt;thermometers and hygrometers&lt;/a&gt; in the enclosure. One at each end, so that I can always have a feel for what is going on. I plan on getting an infrared thermometer in the future, but right now these are working well and I am making sure that it stays above 50%. So far with the coconut husks and the fact that I myself prefer at least 50% humidity, this isn't a problem. Melusina's enclsure is in a room where I have a giant 3.5 gallon humdifier that I have set up for my own personal comfort, I understand not everyone does this though, so you might have to take other measure to keep your snake happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have two &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2kIadjK"&gt;hides&lt;/a&gt; for her, and she spends a lot of the day in them. The hides are identical. As I learned, hides should be the same size, and those hollowed out logs don't really give them security, even if one end is butted up against glass. So far Melusina really likes the ones I have for her. You can use pretty much anything for hides as long as they are the same size. The reason for this is that in the wild a snake could have its pick of hides, and so will look for one that meets its temperate and size needs for its own security. If one is too small or too big, it can go find another one. In captivity, a snake can't be Goldilocks. The snake can really only pick between the hides that we give. So if the snake feels safe in the warm hide, but needs to thermoregulate and be cooler, the snake might have to choose between feeling safe and thermoregulating. She has some fake plants, too. Most of which I bought in the fish section, because for some reason they were cheaper. She also has a fake log that stays in the middle of the tank that she will sometimes climb on at night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for food, I order her food online. Be warned, the shipping is a big pricy, and it will come packaged with dry ice. But the mice and rats themselves are pretty cheap. I bought her 50 frozen prey for $12, plus $50 shipping. The breeder suggested to me &lt;a href="http://www.perfectprey.com/"&gt;PerfectPrey&lt;/a&gt; but there are other places you can buy too. I can't so far find frozen prey local to me (which is weird, this is a major city…but I guess DC is a fairly conservative city as far as pets go?). I also picked up some tongs which I use to hold the prey when I attempt to feed her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feed her frozen/thawed mice, which was what the breeder also fed her. Ball pythons are docile, shy, and not always interested in food. Live feeding can be lethal to the snake if the snake isn't wanting to feed and the prey is wanting to fight, especially if the prey is a bigger rat. The prey items are humanely killed and then I thaw them, warm them up to a body temperature without cooking them, and then feed to Melusina. I also feed her in her enclosure, there is no need to move a snake to a different tank to feed them. This way the snake isn't stressed out from being somewhere else. Feeding in the enclosure won't cause "cage aggression" and won't train your snake to think you hand is food every time you open the cage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few more things: you can also apparently &lt;a href="https://ball-pythons.net/forums/showthread.php?139156-Vypyrz-Tub-Set-Up-The-Basics-*DUW*"&gt;use sterilite or rubbermaid bins as snake enclosures&lt;/a&gt;, they hold heat and humidity better than glass tanks, and you can do pretty much the same set up, with some accomodations for making sure the under tank heaters don't melt the plastic. You use a soldering iron to put some holes in the side, and make sure it has secure clips to keep the lid on. If it doesn't, you can use luggage thing ma bobs to keep it closed. The draw back is you don't have the crystal clear view of your snake. It's cheap though! The PVC enclosures I talked about earlier have the crystal clear view of glass, and the heat/humidity retention of bins. Some of the links that I saw posted over and over again in reddit were really helpful to me, and they might be helpful to you too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://reptimes.com/ball-pythons-the-basics-and-then-some/"&gt;The Basics and Then Some&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://reptimes.com/ball-pythons-common-problems/"&gt;Ball Python Common Problems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://reptimes.com/ball-pythons-feeding/"&gt;Ball Pythons Feeding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've sure learned a lot about snake keeping, and I hope if you have the means, you go for the PVC enclosures, but if you are like me and already have all the stuff for a glass tank, hopefully this can help you get a good set up until you can afford to make a change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh…and about my partner that is terrified of snakes? Totally in love with Melusina now &amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cover Reveal!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/Cover-Reveal/"/>
    <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog/Cover-Reveal/</id>
    <published>2017-01-24T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-01-25T18:27:19-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dax Murray</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's here! The cover for &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01MS9NU7F/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1484938920&amp;amp;sr=1-1"&gt;The Resignation Letter&lt;/a&gt; !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/ResignationLetterCover-01.jpg" alt="cover image: a white woman in a gown reclines on a chaise lounge, while a black woman stands in front of scientific tools looking into a magical orb" style="max-width:100%;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Isn't it &lt;em&gt;gorgeous&lt;/em&gt;? &lt;a href="https://juneberrydesign.myportfolio.com/"&gt;Louisa of Juneberry Designs&lt;/a&gt; did a fabulous job getting the look and feel of the characters, and setting up the world, too. Seriously, you should chat with Louisa if you need a cool cover for your books! Having a cover makes it feel much more exciting as the release date draws near! Today for a brief moment the book was in the top rankings on Kindle in several categories. Specifically, in the #1 spot for Kindle Store -&amp;gt; Kindle Short Reads -&amp;gt; 30 Minutes (12 - 21 pages -&amp;gt; LGBT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/kindle_rankings_01_25_17.jpeg" alt="Kindle rankings, #1 in Shorts LGBT, #6 in Science Fiction and Fantasy, and #18 in Literature and Fiction" style="max-width:100%;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've also gotten an advance &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1888708702?book_show_action=true"&gt;review on Goodreads&lt;/a&gt; and I hope y'all will take the time to read and review!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;"…all of the prose is beautifully written and overall, this is a pleasure to read."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've got a novella in the works right now, and hope to get it published before summer (before I will officially be consummed by &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy XIV: Stormblood&lt;/em&gt;). It's one of those dreaded Fairy Tale Retellings. Of course, my version is going to be full of queer people and won't be all white people. I also wanted to send a shout out to someone I forgot to mention in my last post! I wanted to thank Erin Lynn Jeffreys Hodges, who provided a lot of technical and technology related assistance, as well as cheerleading and pom pom waving! Thanks, Erin!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Resignation Letter Announcement and Miscellany</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/The-Resignation-Letter-Announcement/"/>
    <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog/The-Resignation-Letter-Announcement/</id>
    <published>2017-01-19T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2017-01-20T14:34:08-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dax Murray</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Big news! I am publishing a short story as a Kindle Select ebook! It is titled &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01MS9NU7F/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1484938920&amp;amp;sr=1-1"&gt;The Resignation Letter&lt;/a&gt;, a fantasy story about class, war, love, magic, and tough choices. You can add it to your TBR on &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/33955963-the-resignation-letter?from_search=true"&gt;goodreads&lt;/a&gt;. I've been working on this short story for awhile, and would like to thank &lt;a href="http://www.kathowardbooks.com/"&gt;Kat Howard&lt;/a&gt; for her editing on some of my initial drafts, and &lt;a href="https://juneberrydesign.myportfolio.com/"&gt;Louisa of Juneberry Designs&lt;/a&gt; for the fantastic cover. I'd also like to thank my paramours for their support, and for encouraging me with squees as they read drafts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is hopefully the first of many queer short stories that I plan on publishing in ebook format. For now, you can pre-order the book on Amazon. (Please note the placeholder cover should be gone soon, and the fabulous cover should take it's place!) The long and the short of the story is queer in a fantasy setting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a more technical note, you may have noticed I haven't reviewed a book here in awhile. I was busy working as a software engineer at the Democratic National Committee, which was a really intense job with really long hours! While I had some time to read here and there, it wasn't as much as I usually have, so no time to review.  I hope to maybe do some back-log reviewing in the coming weeks. Also, I may still blog here about code occassionally, but most of my coding stuffy is being moved to &lt;a href="http://dax.codes"&gt;dax.codes&lt;/a&gt;, so here should be mostly feminism and books. You can also find more of my cats now at &lt;a href="http://dax.cat"&gt;dax.cat&lt;/a&gt;. MY CATS ARE WEBSCALE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last detail: I came out as genderqueer, and I am in the process of changing my name. I go by Dax now, you might find some references throughout this site to my old name still, or links to accounts of mine I still haven't changed to reflect my new name. Changing names is a lot of work and a lot of time. Forgive these brief discrepencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solidarity!&lt;br /&gt;
Dax&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Review: The Insurrectionist and the Empress Who Reigns Over Time by Benjanun Sriduangkaew</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/Review-The-Insurrectionist-And-The-Empress-Who-Reigns-Over-Time/"/>
    <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog/Review-The-Insurrectionist-And-The-Empress-Who-Reigns-Over-Time/</id>
    <published>2015-09-16T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-12-29T10:50:39-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dax Murray</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This short story is available for free on Beneath the Ceaseless Sky's website. You can also pay for it on Amazon so you can read it on your Kindle. I did the latter because 1.) It's so good you should support it financially and 2.) I prefer e-ink to backlit screens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"The Insurrectionist and the Empress Who Reigns Over Time" was written specifically to show you can have bad things happen to people, but not make it about the bad things happening because the characters are queer. There is a pattern in fiction, television, movies, where many queer people are shown as so good and pure, by virtue of being queer, that bad things must happen to them to show how cruely the world treats them. They are "too good for this sinful earth" or the authorial intent is to showcase how bad homophobia, biphobia and transphobia are. For me, and others, fiction is an escape from this world. Benjanun Sriduangkaew tweeted out that she intended to show that the bad acts that happen to characters can happen for reasons that are not tied to their sexuality or gender, and that those same characters can also have happy endings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel that "Insurrectionist" accomplished this goal. Benjanun Sriduangkaew did an excellent job of creating a world that felt huge, but not giving the reader the long, rambling history of the world, all of its people, and what the cook makes at every meal. True, this is a short story, so that is the goal. But all of the characters felt real, and while you might not know what happened in some distant past to make them the way they are today, you had enough context to know that their behavior was not arbitrary, and based on plot necessity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Insurrectionist" is the story of a woman who leads uprisings against current governments by working to make rebellions look natural, she uses words and speeches to change the opinions of people. Her greatest gift is her ability to bend words. One day, however, her luck runs out. She is captured, her mouth sewn shut, and imprisoned by an Empress from a kingdom near the one she'd just conquered. The Empress, as the  reader may have guessed, has her own unique abilities. She can move time, and wishes to change a key event. As the Insurrectionist and the Empress figure out how they might be useful to each other, they also figure out they are also attracted to each other. At the end, they find a solution that satisfyingly resolves both of their inner conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This short story is not just noteworthy for having two women who are attracted to women as the main characters. The Empress has two mothers, one assumes from the terms that her one mothers is a trans woman, and the other a cis woman. It was incredibly normal to all of the characters involved. Of course the Empress had a giving-mother, and a bearing-mother. Of course that is a normal family structure. It's also evident that the Empress's current situation, her current emotions and thoughts, are not the result of bad parenting or the result of having a unique-to-the-reader family structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I believe this is the best short story I've read so far in 2015. The writing is beautiful, some beautiful child of poetry and prose. The pacing is perfect for a story about displacement in time, and the pacing served to further that sense of displacement that the Insurrectionist feels. The characters were real and experienced loss and tragedy in the their lives, but never was that loss inextricably tied to their sexuality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read this short story if you are a human with a soul. Don't read this short story if you are a a huge transphobe.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Review: Witches and Wolves by Kelly D. Smith</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://daxmurray.com/blog/Review-Witches-and-Wolves/"/>
    <id>http://daxmurray.com/blog/Review-Witches-and-Wolves/</id>
    <published>2015-09-15T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-12-29T10:50:39-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dax Murray</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I received an ARC copy of 'Witches and Wolves' from NetGalley in exchange for an honest review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;'Witches and Wolves' was a fun novella about learning to be yourself and falling in love. The story focuses on Tory, a witch who lives in the wood to get away from the city life; Tory's ex-boyfriend, a werewolf who also enjoys the seclusion of the woods; and Gee, a young woman who is new to being a werewolf. Gee is just learning how to control her wolf, and finds herself on Tory's doorstep one night. With the help of her new friends, she learns how to embrace who she is, and also finds herself falling for Tory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought this story was well paced, and the contrast between the external conflicts and the internal conflicts worked to highlight and enhance the inner struggles Gee was going through. I also appreciated that the potential love triangles were not those of most fiction today, and the bisexuality of Tory was not a point of contention for anyone. It's really refreshing to have a bisexual character who is allowed to be human, and isn't subjected to doubt or mistrust from any potential, new, or former lover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed the world-building, too. I felt there was enough details to get a sense of the world without being bogged down in unnecessary backstory or long pages of history. I got enough backstory for the world to know what was relavant to the plot, and a few additional tidbits to make the world of witches, werewolves, and werewolf hunters seem real, interesting, and detailed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through and through, this was a romance story. There was a side plot to solidify the relationship between Gee and Tory, and I enjoyed it. My criticisms would be the length, as I thought it was a bit too short. I would have liked to have a few more intimate scenes between the two of them (not intimate in terms of sexy times, but a few more touching moments).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read this book if you like werewolves and witches falling in love. Don't read this book if you are a fan of the "Bury your gays" trope, and "bisexuals don't exist" tropes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
